Chapter 1: A Chance Meeting and Welcome

It was Year 1000 of the Holy Era, in early spring.

A giant eagle-like bird was soaring through the skies above the spirit folk village; it was Ariel, the contract spirit of Orphia, the high elf girl. Four girls in total were riding on Ariel’s back.

“Orphia, faster! Faster!” Latifa, the werefox, urged Orphia to make Ariel move faster.

“Got it. Ariel, if you’d please,” Orphia ordered Ariel, smiling with amusement. With a great flap of her wings, Ariel accelerated her flight speed.

“Hey, Latifa — there’s no need to rush. It’s not like Rio’s going to run away,” Sara, the silver werewolf who was also riding on Ariel, said with an exasperated face.

“But I want to be the first one to greet Onii-chan!” Latifa pouted her lips cutely.

“There he is.” The dwarf girl Alma, who had been silently watching the ground from Ariel’s back as they moved, spotted the people they were looking for and pointed toward them. There in the distance stood five boys and girls — Rio and his guests.

Onii-chan. And those people must be... Latifa enhanced her vision with spirit arts and focused her eyes on all of their faces. Rio and the others must have noticed their approach, as they were all looking back.

“The peach-haired girl seems to be Lady Aishia. Ariel is drawing back a little,” Orphia said in awe.

“My Hel is also acting a little weird. Is it because of Lady Aishia? Alma, how about your Ifritah?”

“Same here. I’m not surprised — she is a humanoid spirit. Her rank really must be high.” Sara and Alma also seemed to feel the abnormality from their contract spirits residing within them in spirit form.

As they were speaking, Ariel closed the distance to Rio’s group. Once they arrived in the skies above him, they began to slowly circle the area and lower their altitudes.

Latifa fidgeted impatiently while waiting for the landing, then jumped off Ariel’s back while they were still a fair distance above the ground.

“Ah, hey! Hold it right there, Latifa! Good grief!” Sara immediately noticed and yelled for her to stop, but Latifa had already landed on the ground. She adjusted her balance and set her eyes on Rio before she took a small breath and burst into an energetic dash.

“Welcome back, Onii-chan!”

“Whoa, there. I’m back, Latifa.” Rio caught Latifa gently, killing the force of her impact. Miharu, Aki, and Masato stared at the two of them, having been somewhat taken by surprise.

“Ehehe,” Latifa grinned shyly. Ariel landed right beside them, and Sara, Orphia, and Alma all jumped down to the ground.

“Geez, Latifa. You know it’s dangerous to jump from so high up, right?” Sara scolded Latifa with a hand placed against her hip.

“It’s fine! I made sure to enhance my physical body beforehand.”

“Geez! ...Oh, forgive my rudeness!” Sara was about to launch into one of her lectures when she noticed the eyes fixed on her. She bowed her head in a fluster, then cleared her throat with a small cough. She smiled brightly to hide her embarrassment and addressed Miharu and the others.

“Welcome to the spirit folk village — we are pleased to have you here.”

Rio chuckled. “This is Sara. She’s a werebeast of the silver wolf variety and from one of the more prominent families in the village.”

“It’s nice to meet you. I’m Sara,” she greeted with a faint blush to her cheeks.

“This is the high elf Orphia, and next to her is Alma, a dwarf. Both of them are from prominent families in the village, just like Sara,” Rio continued.

“Nice to meet you.”

“It’s a pleasure.”

Orphia and Alma both bowed politely in greeting.

“Umm, my name is Ayase Miharu. Pleased to make your acquaintance,” Miharu replied rather nervously.

“I’m Sendo Aki. Nice to meet you,” Aki greeted awkwardly.

“Whoa... They’re real.” Masato let out a squeaky noise as he stared at Sara and the others in a captivated daze.

“...You introduce yourself properly, too,” Aki said, poking Masato in the head roughly.

“O-Oww, that hurts. What’s your problem, Aki?” Masato complained as he held a hand up to where he was poked, but Aki didn’t bother responding to him.

“Please accept my apologies — this is my foolish brother, Masato. As you can see, he is lacking in many areas, but he doesn’t mean anything by it. I would appreciate it if you treat him with some level of tolerance,” Aki explained and bowed her head at Sara and the others in embarrassment.

“Fufu, that’s all right,” Orphia nodded with a giggle. Rio looked at the three Japanese visitors and introduced them to Latifa, who was still in his arms.

“This is Latifa. We’re not related by blood, but she’s my beloved little sister. She should be the same age as Aki.”

“I’m Latifa. Onii-chan’s little sister, and a werefox. Pleased to meet you.” Latifa adjusted her posture and bowed to them with a bashful smile, then raised her head and glanced at Miharu and Aki’s faces.

“Hello, Latifa. It’s wonderful meeting you,” Miharu said, returning Latifa’s grin.

“...Yes,” Latifa nodded hesitantly, enchanted by Miharu’s smile.

“Now, I’ll introduce this girl to Sara and the others. You may have figured it out already, but this is my contract spirit, Aishia. Aishia, can you introduce yourself to them?” Rio asked.

“Hello. I’m Aishia,” she said simply.

“It’s an honor to finally make your acquaintance, Lady Aishia. On behalf of all the spirit folk, we welcome you to our village.” Sara, Orphia, and Alma all kneeled respectfully where they stood. In response to their reverent reaction, Aishia tilted her head curiously. Miharu and the others also seemed taken aback.

Chapter 2: New Life in the Village

The afternoon of the day after Miharu and the others began their new lives in the spirit folk village...

Rio held a training sword in his hand as he stood with Sara, Alma, and Orphia, all four of them gathered in the square before the town hall. At the request of Sara and the other girls, they were about to have a sparring match.

Beside them, the winged werebeast and warrior chief of the village, Uzuma, was acting as the referee, while Miharu, Aki, Masato, and Latifa were observing from a short distance away. The children of the village, led by Vera and Arslan, were running over after hearing the rumors of what was about to happen. However, Aishia had gone to visit Dryas and wasn’t present.

They checked the condition of the training equipment before their match, warming up lightly first. “Rio, would you be okay with a one-on-three match? I’d like you to check our coordination as a group today,” Sara asked as she grabbed a training dagger.

Rio nodded immediately. “Sure, I don’t mind. I wanted to practice facing multiple opponents more anyway.”

“Hey, is one-on-three a proper match? Sara and the others aren’t that strong, are they?” Masato asked Arslan, who stood next to him; they were watching the whole exchange from the sidelines. After the banquet and a night of sleeping under the same roof together, he seemed to have warmed up to Sara and the others enough not to call them “miss” anymore.

Arslan corrected Masato’s misunderstanding rather excitedly. “Stupid, Sara and the other girls are pretty strong, too... But Rio’s just too strong.” His eyes shined brightly as he imagined the exciting match that was about to unfold before them.

“Really...”

“Like I said before, Rio’s strong enough to be the very best fighter in the village. Just watch carefully.”

“Y-Yeah. Seems like it’s starting now.” Arslan’s words and the mood in the air seemed to reach Masato, as he nodded rather nervously in return. Right before his eyes, Rio and the girls were facing each other and bracing their weapons.

“Begin!” Uzuma called out, giving the signal to begin the match. Immediately after, Sara’s figure all but disappeared as she burst into a run toward Rio.

“So fast!!” Masato, Aki, and Miharu gazed in shock at the speed that far surpassed their imagination as Sara resolutely swung her dagger and aimed multiple attacks at Rio. Her aim seemed to be to pin him in place, as her series of blows placed more emphasis on speed rather than power and precision.

However, Rio managed to avoid those attacks splendidly. He deflected the minimum amount of attacks with his sword, while the rest he evaded lightly with the ways he positioned his body.

“Fuh!” Alma, who had been hiding behind Sara with her small frame, drew near Rio and tried to land a heavy blow with her mace. However, Rio seemed to be expecting Alma’s movements in advance, as he stepped back easily to avoid her attack. Alma’s mace cut through the air with a sharp sound and bore into the ground; the sound of the soil being pulverized echoed belatedly.

“W-Wow! But wouldn’t you die if that hit you?!” Masato yelled, flustered at how Alma’s herculean strength didn’t suit her small stature.

“It’s fine! They’ve enhanced their physical bodies. There’s spirit arts for healing, too,” Arslan explained excitedly.

Alma easily swung her blunt mace that didn’t suit her build, attempting to land her attacks on Rio. However, she seemed to be lacking in speed, as he easily evaded all of them. That was where Sara came in; she continued to launch her sharp attacks against Rio, covering for Alma’s wider gestures.

The speed fighter Sara and power fighter Alma — if Rio focused on one of them, the other would come in to back them up, freeing their movements. Their roles were clearly separated, showing splendid coordination. Furthermore, Rio’s mind had to be split across one more opponent.

“I’d like to join the fun too,” Orphia said, politely interrupting them as she fired a series of light bullets she had spread out around her toward Rio. Their appearance and individual force were identical to the low grade offensive magic of Photon Projectilis, but their trajectory twisted and turned freely instead of moving in a straight line.

Rio finally burst into a run to avoid the bullets, but Sara and Alma had promptly closed in on both his sides, obstructing his path to safety. At that, Rio immediately stopped evading. He drew the bullets as close to him as possible before stomping down on the ground heavily. No sooner had he done that, a thick dirt wall rose from the ground before him and blocked the light projectiles; he had poured essence into his feet to manipulate the ground with spirit arts.

However, Sara and Alma instinctually expected the fact that he would defend himself and broke into a run right away, closing in on Rio in a pincer attack. Rio glanced left and right, before thrusting his sword into the ground and choosing to brace himself unarmed. His actions even made Sara and the other onlookers a bit taken aback with surprise.

Rio didn’t let that moment of weakness escape him. He instantly pulled his sword out of the ground and approached Alma first, moving to intercept her. Alma swung her mace reflexively, but Rio braced his sword sideways and spun his body, using his centrifugal force to swing his sword. Immediately after, Rio’s sword clashed with Alma’s mace, ringing with a tremendous impact.

Sweat dripped from Alma’s forehead. “To think you’d directly challenge a dwarf like me in a test of strength...” Dwarves boasted the highest level of monstrous strength among the spirit folk species, but she and Rio were completely equal in power just now.

“That’s because you’re a girl. I can’t afford to lose in a test of strength.” Rio smiled with a chuckle. By effortlessly withdrawing his sword, he cleverly threw Alma off balance.

“Huh? Kya?!”

When she lost her balance, Alma let out a cute sound that was normally unheard from her. She just barely managed to swing her mace, but Rio stepped deeply into her personal space and reached a hand out to gracefully parry her mace, snatching it and flinging it far away.

“Uh?!”

With a faint smile, Rio explained why the spirit folk trio were acting with such humility. “Like I told you before, the spirit folk consider high-ranking spirits that have a humanoid form to be sacred, and worship them. You’re one of those humanoid spirits, Aishia.”

“I don’t need to be treated so stiffly,” Aishia said, shaking her head quietly.

“Well, I know you can’t just agree with that so easily, but it’d be nice if you could take appropriate measures for that. For now, please stand up,” Rio said to Sara’s group, the faint smile still on his face.

“...Okay.” The villagers nodded, standing hesitantly. “Umm, then... May I call you Aishia?” Latifa asked Aishia without faltering.

“Geez, there you go acting all overly familiar again. Try and follow the spirit folk ways for once...” Sara sighed tiredly and expressed her disapproval, but—

“Latifa can call me whatever she likes. I don’t mind if you call me Aishia,” Aishia answered nonchalantly.

“Oh.” Sara was immediately at a loss for words.

“Hmm... Then, Aishia, is it?” Latifa cocked her head and hummed to herself.

“Yep, that’s me.”

“Yay! I’m glad to meet you, Aishia!”

“U-Umm, Rio. Are you sure this is okay?” Sara looked at Rio worriedly for confirmation.

“It’s fine. Miharu even calls her Ai-chan.” Rio gave Sara his stamp of approval with an amused smile.

“...Really?” Sara stared at Miharu fixedly, as though she was seeing something awe-inspiring.

“Huh? Sh-Should I not have been doing that, by any chance?” Miharu asked nervously, trembling with a start.

“You’re fine. Aishia herself told you it was fine, so please respect her opinion.” Rio shook his head cheerfully as he consoled Miharu.

“Umm, by the way. When they say ‘Rio,’ are they talking about you, Haruto?” Aki suddenly asked, having been listening silently for a while. At the same time, Latifa’s ears twitched at the sound of Aki calling Rio “Haruto.”

“Ah, that’s right. I still have to explain the circumstances around that properly.” Rio scratched at his head with a troubled expression, unsure of where to start. Latifa watched him silently at his side.

“I mentioned it indirectly when I first met you guys, but ‘Haruto’ is the alias I am using while I’m active in the Strahl region. My real name is the one Sara and the others have been calling me — Rio,” he explained.

Sara raised her hand hesitantly. “Erm, may I ask why you need to use two names separately?”

“It goes back to several years ago, before I first visited this village. I was involved in some trouble with the royalty and nobility of a certain kingdom in Strahl. They made me into a scapegoat for a crime I did not commit. In the end, they even put out a wanted notice for me,” Rio replied uncomfortably. At that, Latifa’s expression fell with an apologetic look.

“Huh?!” The other girls all widened their eyes. Only Aishia remained indifferent to his story, having known what happened already.

Ah! Sara and the other spirit folk girls recalled how they had been told of Latifa’s past as an assassin who had tried to attack Rio. Expressions of understanding fell across their faces as they began to suspect that the incident may have been related to how Latifa and Rio had met.

“Well, I know it doesn’t sound very believable...” Rio said with a troubled face after a moment, the faces around him appearing dumbfounded.

“Of course we believe you. We’re just shocked at how horrible it must have been.” Sara shook her head in a fluster.

“It really is horrible. Is that wanted status still in effect even now?” Alma asked with a frown.

“Thank you for your concern. I’m not sure if the warrant is still active... I haven’t returned to that kingdom yet, after all. However, the crime wasn’t a light one, and its statute of limitations wouldn’t have run out after a mere few years. Even if they aren’t actively searching for me, I think it’d be best to consider the crime as still pertinent.” Rio shook his head slowly.

“I see. So that’s why you decided to use two names and change your hair color with a magic artifact...” Sara said, comprehending his words with a conflicted expression.

“It’s also because black hair simply attracts attention in the Strahl region,” Rio added. “But its true purpose is to act as a precaution if that warrant from back then is still effective. So... I don’t mind what you call me while I’m in the village, but Miharu, if you and the others ever return to Strahl with me, I’d like to ask you to only call me ‘Haruto’ there,” he said lightly, clearing the heavy mood. Masato cocked his head.

“Hmm... You’re still Haruto to me, though. It doesn’t feel right to call you Rio at this point, and switching names would just confuse me if we ever go back to Strahl, so I’m going to stick with calling you Haruto!” he said with a grin.

“I’d like to continue calling you Haruto, too, since I’m already used to it,” Miharu agreed with a smile.

“Umm, then... me too.” Aki also nodded hesitantly.

“He has always been Rio to us, so it’s a bit curious to see him being called Haruto,” Sara said with a giggle.

“But it strangely suits him, don’t you think? His gray hair is lovely, too,” Orphia said, smiling cheerfully.

“It’s true... Rio’s aura is a little different when he has gray hair instead of black hair, but they both make him look handsome,” Alma agreed.

“Ah, I think it suits him too, you know?! When I said curious, I didn’t mean it was weird... Wait, what’s that look for, Alma?” Sara hurriedly added on to her earlier comment, but when she spotted Alma’s triumphant expression, she stopped to question the meaning behind it.

“Oh, no reason. Don’t you think it’s time to lead everyone now?” Alma smiled with a puff of laughter and calmly changed the subject. Orphia was giggling, too, as Rio’s guests watched their exchange with deep curiosity.

“I-I know that! And what are you laughing at, Orphia? We’re going to lead everyone now. Hurry up and let them on Ariel’s back.” Sara’s cheeks reddened with embarrassment as she urged Orphia into moving.

◇　◇　◇

The entire group took to the skies and headed toward the giant tree house that was used as the village’s town hall. Once they landed in the square just before the town hall, Miharu and Aki timidly dropped down to the ground, whereas Masato leaped down with enthusiasm.

“That was amaaazing! Flying is so fun! The village buildings are amazing too!” he shouted in high spirits.

Beside him, Aki shot him a look of distaste at his childishness, but she also greatly enjoyed the scenery during their flight, so she wasn’t one to talk, either. Miharu chuckled at the sight of the two.

Just then, particles of light gathered at the entrance of the town hall, taking on the shape of a beautiful woman. “You’ve arrived. I’ve been waiting.” The woman who had materialized was Dryas, the spirit of the giant tree.

“Great Dryas — you’re here.” Sara, Orphia, and Alma bowed at Dryas respectfully.

Dryas approached Aishia and spoke to her with a radiant smile. “Yes, I felt the presence of a powerful spirit appear within the village barrier. I flew over immediately, knowing it had to be Rio’s contracted spirit. You must be the one. I’m Dryas.”

“I’m Aishia. Hello, Dryas,” Aishia replied in a monotonous voice.

Dryas stared into Aishia’s face with a look of contemplation. “Hmm. You really are a spirit I don’t know, then. Not to mention your... Well, it’s fine. Let’s continue this conversation inside. You’re meeting the elders, right?” she asked, then immediately turned on her heel and faced the town hall.

“All right. Follow me, everyone.” Led by Sara and the others, the party headed toward the top floor of the town hall.

◇　◇　◇

Ten minutes later, on the top floor of the town hall in the council room, Aishia and Miharu’s group received a warm welcome from the elders of the village. The three head elders began with simple introductions.

“It is a pleasure to have you in our village, Lady Aishia. On behalf of all the spirit folk, we welcome you from the depths of our hearts.” One of the head elders, the high elf Syldora, stood up from his chair and addressed Aishia sitting in the guest seat with reverence. The other elders also stood and lowered their heads at Aishia out of respect.

“Thanks,” Aishia said shortly.

With a small smile, Syldora turned to greet Miharu, Aki, and Masato sitting beside Aishia. “Children from another world, you have done well coming this far. We welcome you, too.”

“Y-Yes! Umm, thank you very much for agreeing to look after us. We are truly so grateful... I’m not sure what to say.” In contrast to Aishia’s composed manner of gratitude, Miharu bowed her head nervously.

“T-Thank you very much!” Aki and Masato bowed awkwardly after Miharu.

“Hahaha, there’s no need to be so formal. This gathering is to merely exchange simple greetings and to see each other in person. I’m sure you have heard from Lord Rio already, but as long as you to agree to several of our conditions, we will guarantee you a peaceful life here in our village. We will leave formal arrangements for another day.” Syldora gave a good-natured smile as he spoke to the nervous group of humans.

“Hmm. We were told you would be otherworldly folk, but you look just like humans.” The head elder dwarf, Dominic, gazed at Miharu and the others with curious interest.

“Hey, don’t stare at them with your fierce mug. You’re scaring the guests,” Ursula scolded Dominic jokingly.

“W-What?” Shocked, Dominic was at a loss for words. The other elders in the room laughed in amusement, and Miharu and the others followed suit. The air the room became much lighter. Sensing that, Dominic let out a dramatic sigh to show that he wasn’t upset.

“Now, there’s no use in continuing this chatter with the boring elderly folk. Sara, you and the girls can guide them to their lodgings,” Syldora said, turning to address the group.

“Understood. Everyone, follow me.” Sara nodded respectfully before swiftly making her way over to Miharu.

“Huh? Is that all?” Miharu asked in surprise, expecting the meeting to go on for a little longer than that.

“Indeed. Tonight was merely a modest greeting of sorts. Perhaps you could tell us stories of your other world some other time? But first, you should get some rest.” Syldora nodded warmly.

Miharu bowed her head deeply. “Y-Yes. Thank you very much!”

“There’s something I’d like to ask Lord Rio and Lady Aishia. Could the two of you remain here a little longer?” Ursula asked.

Rio nodded immediately, before looking over at Sara and Latifa. “Of course. Everyone, I’m leaving Miharu and the other guests in your hands. You too, Latifa.”

“Sure. You can leave it to me, Onii-chan!” Latifa puffed out her chest proudly.

◇　◇　◇

After Sara and the spirit folk girls led Miharu, Aki, and Masato out of the room, Ursula spoke up.

“My apologies, Lord Rio. Lady Aishia. There are some more complicated matters we’d like to discuss with you, so please keep us old folk company a little longer.”

“Of course, it’s nothing to apologize for. If anything, we should be thanking you for your consideration,” Rio replied with a bow. He figured that the reason why Sara and the others were sent to lead Miharu’s group away was because the topic of the discussion to come was highly confidential.

Right now, the only ones remaining in the room were Rio, Aishia, the council of elders, and Dryas, the spirit of the giant tree. All were more than qualified to know what was being discussed, and to keep the information to themselves.

“So, what did you wish to discuss?”

“Hm. While there’s a lot to cover, we’ll start with Lady Aishia first. Great Dryas, if you’d do the honors?” Syldora immediately cut to the chase, seeking further instructions from Dryas, who sat next to Aishia.

“Let’s see. First, it’s clear that Aishia isn’t any spirit that I know of. From what I’ve heard through the elders, Rio’s mentioned a few odd points here and there, too... Aishia, is it true you don’t have any memory of what kind of spirit you are?”

Aishia nodded. “Yup.”

“That’s what I found odd. Normally, a spirit would retain their memories from before they ranked up to a humanoid state, but she doesn’t have any memories, not even of her name. It seems she has the awareness and intellect of a humanoid spirit, but her sense of self seems strangely weak... I suppose that’s because of the amnesia?” Dryas contemplated out loud.

“...I’d like to ask you something about that. Are all spirits capable of climbing the ranks up to a humanoid state, all while keeping their memories from the lower and middle ranks?” Rio asked.

“That’s a difficult question. I can only tell you based on what I’ve seen myself, so this may not be the correct answer, but not every spirit can climb to a rank higher than they’re already at. There are many components and conditions required,” Dryas replied. “I’m not entirely certain with regard to the memories, either, but I know I can’t remember anything from when I was a low-ranked spirit myself. Spirits are normally said to be mana that hold a clear sense of self, but low-ranked spirits are basically the equivalent of a human baby in terms of cognizance. I only have memories from after I became a middle-ranked spirit. Although, I couldn’t wander very far from the tree I resided in at the time, so I basically spent every day sunbasking,” she added, looking wistful as she spoke.

“Thank you for your answer. In other words, Aishia should have had a stage before she became a humanoid spirit, and she should have memories of that period.”

“That’s right. I should add that once a spirit reaches the upper-middle ranks, it takes many long years to strengthen their sense of self and gain individuality. Just like me,” Dryas said, smiling proudly.

“I see...” Rio nodded in understanding, then looked at Aishia. She indeed had a personality that was quite different compared to Dryas’. Unlike Dryas, who freely expressed her emotions, Aishia didn’t show many of her emotions outwardly.

“That’s why... How should I put this? Aishia... She almost seems like a young spirit that just ranked up from being a low ranking spirit to a middle ranked one. Her rank as a spirit is high, but her sense of self seems weak and irregular. Unless she’s actually a really eccentric girl beneath that exterior... but she isn’t, is she?” Dryas said thoughtfully, looking at Aishia with an incline of her head.

“Am I?” Aishia tilted her head, too, looking at Rio.

“Who knows. But, I think you’re already very charming as you are.” Rio laughed in amusement.

“Thank you, Haruto.” Aishia smiled faintly; Dryas watched their exchange.

“Fufu, it seems like your contract relationship is going well. That’s a good thing. I don’t have anyone I’m contracted to, so it makes me a little jealous,” she said pleasantly.

“Indeed, she does seem to have opened to Lord Rio a fair amount,” Ursula agreed. “However... Does she mean Lord Rio when she says ‘Haruto’?”

“Yes. Due to certain circumstances, I’ve been calling myself Haruto while in the Strahl region. I informed Sara and the others earlier, but this is a good chance to inform everyone here, too.” Rio said, then repeated everything he had told the girls earlier. The elders listened to him in silence, only speaking up once he had finished his explanation.

“I see. So Lord Rio had that kind of past...” Ursula murmured with a conflicted expression. The other elders wore similar looks on their faces.

“I’m sorry. I didn’t mean to keep it a secret all this time, but I didn’t think it was a good story to spread around, so I kept quiet about it. With the circumstances as they are right now, you deserved an explanation... but it isn’t a very positive story, I admit. Please do not let it weigh down on you,” Rio apologized with a guilty expression. “There’s one more thing I need to explain to everyone that might not be very pleasant... It’s the reason why I was able to communicate with Miharu. I’d like to ask you to keep what I’m about to say as confidential as possible — is that all right?”

The three head elders looked at each other with wide eyes. “...Are you sure? There’s no need to force yourself to explain anything.” Syldora asked, watching Rio’s expression.

“I’m not forcing myself into anything. However, it isn’t the type of explanation I expect to be taken seriously, so you may find what I’m about to say to be rather strange. If Miharu, Aki, and Masato hadn’t appeared, I would have never told anyone about this,” Rio said with a troubled expression.

“Does this mean you’ve told the otherworlders this, too?”

“Yes. The need for an explanation was unavoidable due to the course of events. That is why I think it would only be right if I gave everyone here the same explanation, since they will be under the care of your village from now on. I omitted my reasons from our talks the other day, but I am willing to explain everything today, if everyone so wishes.”

“I see... Everyone, it is as you have just heard. If Lord Rio discusses this with us, it will be strictly forbidden to speak of this outside of this room. Those who cannot vow their silence should leave this room immediately,” Syldora said. Once he confirmed that not a single person had left their seat, he spoke up again, smiling at the elders. “Then it is assumed that everyone present has sworn to strictly adhere to the aforementioned conditions. Those who break their word... Well, you all know what happens. Great Dryas, you are fine with this, too?”

“I don’t mind. I have neither the interest nor gossip partner to do so,” Dryas agreed with a nod.

“It seems we are all in compliance, Lord Rio. Now, would you please tell us what you have to say?” Syldora asked, looking at Rio.

“Of course. I am greatly obliged for your consideration.”

Rio bowed deeply, then began to explain the reason why he could communicate with Miharu in Japanese — because he had memories of his own previous life — but only to the extent of what he already told Miharu and the other Japanese visitors. Specifically, he told the elders how he had awoken to memories that weren’t his own when he was a young child, and that those memories were set in a world that was coincidentally the same as the world that Miharu had been living in. He hid the fact that he had a connection to Miharu in his previous life.

“That’s all,” Rio said, wrapping up his explanation. The elders had remained silent for the entire duration of Rio’s speech, but the moment he was done, they all inhaled at once — as though just remembering to breathe.

Syldora was the first to open his mouth. “Hmm. That is indeed an unexpected tale to believe... but it is the truth, no?” After a heavy moment of thought, he accepted Rio’s words as truth.

“...You believe me?” Rio’s asked in amazement, having not expected anyone to believe him so easily.

“It’s because you’re the one saying this, Lord Rio — that is enough for us to believe you. Not to mention, it seems to be true that you were able to communicate in their language. Even if you were to lie about it, there would be no need to make up a story this nonsensical to cover it up.” Syldora nodded with a wry smile.

“However, it is indeed nonsensical. I can understand why Lord Rio wants us to keep this truth confidential... Being reborn with your memories is something I have never heard of before in my long years of life.” Ursula said, also with a wry smile.

“Right...” Rio acknowledged how impossible it sounded.

Dominic placed a hand by his chin. “Hmm. Great Dryas, have you ever encountered anyone in a similar situation as this before?” he asked her, since she was the oldest living being in the village.

Dryas shook her head bluntly. “I haven’t. As far as I know, no one like that has ever appeared in this village before.”

“Is that so... Sorry, Rio. I was hoping there’d be a precedent that could provide you with hints, but alas.” Dominic shrugged his shoulders at the hopeless situation.

Rio shook his head with a smile. “No, it’s still of great use to me to know that no one like this has openly appeared throughout the long history of the world. I wondered if it was possible my memories of my previous life had something to do with how I suddenly found myself contractually bound to Aishia without realizing it, but I’ll set that thought aside for now.”

He already knew of someone who had memories of their previous life, and another that he highly suspected to be the case, but he decided not to reveal that right now.

“Hmm... If only we at least knew what kind of spirit Aishia was... All I can say for certain is that she isn’t a part of the only high rank spirit network I know. By the way, what kind of element do you specialize in, Aishia?” Dryas suddenly asked.

“All of them,” Aishia replied calmly. At that, the elders all stirred noisily. Even Dryas, the one who asked the question, widened her eyes in astonishment. Rio was the only one who was confused, wondering why everyone was reacting with such surprise.

Dryas repeated her question nervously. “...Umm, I’m not sure I heard you correctly. Did you just say you specialize in all types of spirit arts?”

◇　◇　◇

While Rio met with the village elders and the Great Dryas, Miharu’s group was being led outside the town hall by the spirit folk girls. In front of the town hall was a wide and spacious square that doubled as a playground for the children. They had missed them earlier, when they had first arrived, but there were young boys and girls running all over, now.

“The scenery was amazing to see from above, but it’s just as amazing from below, too. The spirit folk really are incredible... They even made a tree house that looks like this. It’s almost like a skyscraper,” Masato said in awe as he looked up at the tree house that was used as the town hall.

He had spoken in Japanese on the spur of the moment, but Orphia was able to pick up on the general gist of Masato’s statement through his reaction. She smiled pleasantly.

“Fufu, the giant tree of Great Dryas is several times the size of this one, you know?” she said in the Strahl tongue.

“Huh? W-Wow, even more... than this? Umm, I would love to see it, if that’s not too much trouble.” Sensing that he was the one being spoken to, Masato blushed, his reply awkward.

“Wipe that sloppy look off your face... Speaking like you’re someone you’re not.” Aki said, looking at Masato with disgust in her eyes.

“W-What’s your problem, Aki? This is my normal way of speaking,” Masato objected in a high-pitched voice, making Aki sneer with a laugh.

“You say that, but your true colors are showing already.”

Meanwhile, Sara and the others hadn’t quite picked up on what was happening yet, so they looked curiously to Miharu for an explanation.

“Ah, umm. Masato is actually quite shy around strangers. I believe he was a little nervous when talking to Orphia...” Miharu explained.

“M-Miharu, you don’t have to tell them that!” Masato yelled in embarrassment.

“It’s not quite shyness around strangers... Masato’s weak to cute and beautiful women older than him — even more so when they’re strangers he’s meeting for the first time,” Aki explained bluntly.

Taken aback, Masato tried to drown out Aki’s voice. “Wah! Stop it, Aki!”

However, it seemed that the spirit folk girls were able to hear her anyway, as they started giggling.

“Ahaha, I see. Should I be saying ‘thank you,’ then?” Orphia smiled bashfully.

“Ah, geez! I’ll never be able to show my face again!” Masato covered his face and squatted down where he stood; he wanted to dig a hole in the ground and hide in it, but the gesture only made Sara and the other girls giggle even harder.

“What a funny child,” Alma murmured, smiling as she looked at Masato.

“You’ll be fine if you can make jokes like that. No one here will be bothered if they never see your face again anyway, so don’t worry about it. Come on, you’re blocking the way, so stand up already,” Aki cracked a merciless verbal whip at Masato, who was still groaning with shame.

“Ugh, I know that. ...Wait, why are all of those people looking at us?” Masato put on a bold front and stood up, before noticing the village children staring at them from afar; their ages appeared to span from five years old to the early teens.

“They’re probably curious about you, since we rarely have visitors from outside the village,” Sara commented.

“Looks like their morning classes ended and they’re using their time for training and exercise. Vera and Arslan are there too,” Alma said, pointing at the children.

The silver werewolf Vera and werelion boy Arslan stepped out from the crowd and approached the group. “Sister! Are these three people the guests Rio brought along?” Vera asked Sara with a friendly smile.

Out of consideration for Miharu and the others, she was speaking in the common language of Strahl instead of the language of the spirit folk.

“That’s right. We’re giving them a tour of the village.” Latifa nodded with a smile.

“I knew it! They have black hair just like Rio, so I could tell right away. It’s nice to meet you! I’m Sara’s little sister, Vera.” Vera faced the humans and bowed politely as she introduced herself.

“Hello there. My name is Miharu, from the same hometown as Haru... as Rio. It’s a pleasure to meet you,” Miharu returned without missing a beat.

For the record, the truth as to how Miharu and the others had come from another world was information that was known only by the council of elders and certain individuals. Because of that, Miharu had to explain that she and the siblings were all humans from Rio’s hometown. In addition to that, she decided against calling Rio “Haruto” in this situation, since the explanation would be complex.

When Vera saw Miharu’s smile, she widened her eyes and nodded. “Y-Yes. Wah... Isn’t she beautiful, Arslan?”

“D-Don’t ask me!” Arslan shouted with embarrassment from his spot beside her, having been put on the spot. Seeing him flustered, Sara giggled.

“This boy’s name is Arslan. He’s Vera and Latifa’s friend,” Sara said, introducing him to everyone on his behalf.

“...I’m Arslan. Nice to meet you,” Arslan said with a turn of his head, cheeks faintly reddened with a blush.

“I’m Masato. I’m twelve years old.”

“My name is Aki. I’m one year older than Masato, so I’m thirteen.”

“That makes Aki the same age as me, then. I love making new friends my age. I hope we can all get along well,” Vera said with a carefree smile.

“As you can see, the two of them can speak the Strahl tongue, too. They’re good friends with Latifa, so I’m sure you’ll have many chances to interact with them in the future. Please be good friends with them,” Sara added.

“Of course,” Aki and Masato said, nodding in unison.

“By the way, where is everyone heading to now?” Vera asked with a tilt of her head.

“We’re about to take Rio’s guests to the house they’ll be living in while he finishes his talk with the elders,” Alma explained.

“Aww, that sounds nice. I wanna go, too!” Vera replied with jealousy.

Sara shook her head sternly. “You can’t. You two have training after this, don’t you?”

“That’s right, Vera. Today’s the day Uzuma’s teaching us, so it’d be a shame to miss it. Let’s go and visit them later?” Arslan said impatiently, trying to persuade Vera against leaving.

“Hmph, fine then.” Vera backed down reluctantly.

“Hey hey, when you say training, what kind of training is it?” Masato asked with great interest.

“Combat training, of course. Our instructor is the warrior chief of our village, you know?” Arslan answered proudly.

“Combat training, huh...” Masato murmured in awe.

“I use two-handed swords,” Arslan stated. “Can you use any weapons, Masato?”

“No, I’ve never had any kind of training like that before... But I’m interested in it,” Masato replied hesitantly.

“Huh, so you want to learn how to use a sword?” Aki asked in surprise, eyes widening.

“Y-Yeah. We don’t move around much studying all the time, after all.”

“Hmm...”

“W-What? You got a problem with that?”

“As long as it’s not dangerous, I suppose... What do you think, Miharu?” Aki suddenly turned to Miharu with a contemplative look.

“Huh? Umm, I wouldn’t like it if it was dangerous, but I’d want to respect Masato’s choice, too, I think? Ah, but make sure you get permission from Haru... I mean, Rio,” Miharu replied.

“Rio would probably make the ideal instructor. If Masato has the fighting spirit to learn swordcraft seriously, then it may be a good idea to discuss it with him properly,” Sara said in a somewhat resolute tone.

“So, would you say that Haru... that Rio is actually really strong?” Masato inquired, making sure his tone was polite.

“Yes. Not only is he strong in pure close combat abilities, his combat with medium and long range spirit art attacks are clearly strong enough to be the very best of the village,” Sara replied proudly.

“Sara’s even fought with Rio before,” Alma said with a huff of laughter.

“T-That goes for you, too!”

Just as Sara was about start arguing back in a fluster, Orphia stepped in with a gentle smile. “All right, all right. You two have both been working hard in your training, so make sure you show your growth to Rio again later in a proper manner.”

“Maybe I’ll get Rio to face me some time. If Masato learns how to use a sword, we can eventually spar each other, too. I’ll train you up to par,” Arslan said, challenging Masato with a smile.

“You still have a ways to go yourself. It’s far too early for you to be training a beginner,” Sara said to Arslan with an exasperated look.

“Haha, I’d love to spar, though. I’ll try asking Rio, but I’ll be looking forward to our match one day... umm... Arslan!” Masato said somewhat shyly, and Arslan nodded energetically in return.

“Yeah, I’ll be waiting!”

◇　◇　◇

After bidding farewell to Vera and Arslan, the spirit folk girls led their three new guests to their new lodgings. The house — a tree house supported by several trees — was located toward the center of the village, several minutes from the town hall.

“You will be living in this house from now on,” Sara said to Miharu, Aki, and Masato after the party stopped in front of the house.

“...That’s amazing. Is it really okay for us to live in such a wonderful place?” Miharu asked nervously as she looked up at the tree house.

“Of course,” Sara agreed. “This house was vacant to begin with—”

“—as it’s the house Onii-chan and I used to live in together,” Latifa cut in happily.

“Hey. Putting it that way makes it sound like you and Rio lived here alone. We lived here, too, remember?” Sara corrected with a slightly sulky tone. Miharu and the others were all rather taken aback, their eyes wide; Masato especially, who was most surprised of all.

“Umm, is something the matter?” Sara asked hesitantly, noticing the change in expression of the three humans.

“...When you say ‘we,’ do you mean Miss Orphia and Miss Alma, too?” Masato asked quietly. He still seemed rather resistant to acting overly friendly with Sara’s group and couldn’t quite call them by just their names yet. He would surely get over that soon.

“Yes,” Sara replied, nodding curiously.

“T-The five of you?” Masato asked once more in a high-pitched voice.

“Y-Yup,” Sara confirmed, now faltering.

“Wow... I’m jealous,” Masato muttered to himself.

Beside him, Aki furrowed her brows unhappily; with a cold smile pasted on her face, she dug her nails into Masato out of view from Sara and the others.

“What? You’ve been living in a home with a skewed gender ratio until now. Do you have something to complain about?”

“O-Oww, that hurts, Aki,” Masato complained painfully, but Aki quickly withdrew her hand and turned her head away with a huff, ignoring him.

“Fufu, the two of you are close.” Latifa laughed with amusement, watching the two of them.

“No, we’re not. We’re always fighting.” Masato shook his head tiredly.

“That just means you’re close enough to fight,” Alma said with a faint giggle.

“Yup yup, just like Sara and Alma,” Orphia agreed with a cheerful smile, then casually directed her glance at Alma and Sara.

“...Or maybe not. I take that back.” Alma blushed red and muttered with embarrassment.

“Geez, what are you saying? Let’s go inside already,” Sara said tiredly, walking off briskly towards the front door of the house, though her cheeks were also faintly red from the side. Miharu realized Sara was blushing from shyness and smiled to herself.

Latifa tugged on Miharu’s sleeve. “Hm? What’s wrong, Latifa?” Miharu asked gently, smiling at her.

“Umm, may I call you Miharu?” Latifa asked, staring straight up into Miharu’s eyes with a look full of anticipation.

Miharu’s eyes widened for a moment before she happily agreed. “Of course you can.”

“Ehehe. Thank you, Miharu. Tell me lots about Onii-chan!”

“Umm, sure... But wouldn’t you know more about Haruto than I would, Latifa?”

“Mm... that might be true, but I kind of want to hear what Onii-chan looks like from Miharu’s point of view, too. I also want to learn lots about you, and I’d love for you to know more about us, because I want us to become friends quickly,” Latifa said, smiling innocently.

Miharu also gave a relaxed smile. “Fufu. If that’s the case, then... gladly. Let’s get along, Latifa,” she said, nodding.

“Yup! Let’s, Miharu!”

As Latifa and Miharu stayed in place to converse, Sara and the others had already moved to the front door.

“Miharu, Latifa. Is something the matter?” Sara asked the two girls.

“It’s nothing. Hey, when you’re done giving the tour of the house, I want to have tea with everyone! Are there any snacks?” Latifa held Miharu’s hand and started to tug her along as she spoke.

“Yup, there are,” Orphia nodded.

“But only a little, it’s almost time for lunch,” Sara added without missing a beat. Miharu watched their exchange from the side and giggled.

Latifa is such a good girl. Sara and the others are so kind, too.

Miharu had hidden her concerns about moving to the village, so it was a relief to see everything going so smoothly. At that moment, it felt like something good was about to happen. It was just a feeling she had.

After that exchange, Miharu, Aki, and Masato were given a tour of the house interior and chatted with the others until Rio and Aishia finished their discussion. Later on, Vera and Arslan visited as well, forming a close group of similarly aged kids with Latifa, Aki, and Masato. Before long, the time for the banquet was upon them.

◇　◇　◇

Evening reared itself; lead by Sara and the spirit folk girls, Miharu, Aki, and Masato were taken to the town hall once more.

They stepped inside the large dining hall on the bottom floor to find countless round tables set up, each one stocked to the brim with delicious dishes in a buffet-style dinner.

“Oooh, amazing! It looks so good!”

“That looks great! I’m so lucky I get to join in!” Both Masato and Arslan exclaimed at the dishes before them. The two boys got along well and hadn’t taken long to hit it off as friends.

“Masato, stop acting so childishly. It’s disgraceful. The families of the important people in this village prepared this for us today, so you should at least mind your manners,” Aki warned.

“Aki talks like she’s your mom,” Arslan whispered to Masato.

“Right?” Masato whispered back. “She’s always trying to tell me off for every little thing. I can’t stand it.”

“Hey, I can hear you,” Aki said to them, the smile on her face twitching.

“Th-There, there, Aki. Today’s a welcoming party for you, so there’s no need to act all formally, either,” Latifa consoled her, with Vera stepping in as well.

“That’s right. Please relax and make yourself at home.”

Next to where the five younger ones had gathered, Miharu was talking to Sara, Orphia, and Alma. The four of them had also warmed up to each other, but there was still some awkwardness that remained.

“So, you prepared such a wonderful party for us too...” Miharu was looking around the dining hall with widened eyes and a hint of surprise.

“It seems like most of the upper families of the village will be attending. Great Dryas and Lady Aishia will also be present, so it looks like those in charge of food preparation went all-out. That being said, everyone’s just happy to have an excuse to party, so there’s no need to be nervous, Miharu,” Alma said, easing Miharu’s worries. It seemed like she was looking up to Miharu with the same respect she showed for Sara and Orphia.

“It’s exactly as Alma says. Once the alcohol comes out, it’ll become much noisier,” Sara said with a bittersweet smile.

“Ahaha. You might be surprised seeing it for the first time,” Orphia added with the same smile on her lips.

Alma looked around the hall. “Looks like everyone’s arriving now.”

Residents of the village had been streaming through the door continuously for a while now.

“If it isn’t Lady Sara, Lady Orphia, and Lady Alma. Good evening.” The werecat girl Anya appeared and called out to Sara’s group.

“Good evening, Anya,” they replied with a smile.

“Is this cute girl the rumored visitor? The one from Rio’s hometown.”

“Yup, this is Miharu. Miharu, this is Anya, the werecat.”

“It’s nice to meet you, Anya. My name is Miharu. Pleased to make your acquaintance.” Miharu bowed courteously.

Anya stepped closer to Miharu and shook her hand, smiling with amusement. “Nice to meet you, Miharu. Hmm... The girls around Rio are all so cute.”

“Eh, no, that’s not...” Miharu blushed in a fluster.

“The demand for Rio is rather high, after all. Feel free to come to me if you need someone to listen to your troubles.” Anya grinned mischievously, probing for details.

“N-No, umm, I’m fine... I think?” Miharu ducked her head in embarrassment.

“Anya. Stop teasing Miharu,” Sara sighed, warning Anya.

“Okaaay,” Anya drew out, then spotted a friend of hers. “Oh, my friend’s here. Miharu, let me introduce her to you. Hey!”

After that, Miharu chatted with the girls of the village for a while. At the same time, Masato and Aki were also deepening their friendships with the other children that were around their age. The adults of the village watched the younger generation mingling across species with pleasant smiles on their faces.

Once all the guests had gathered, head elder Syldora spoke up. “Now, shall we begin? Everyone, may I ask that you please be silent?” he said, his voice echoing throughout the room; he had amplified his voice with wind spirit arts. The bustling hall immediately fell silent. Syldora, Dominic, and Ursula presided over the dining hall, gathering all the attention of those present.

Once Syldora had the hall’s attention, he spoke with a wry smile as he looked out over those present. “Lady Aishia and Great Dryas will be entering the hall, now. I believe everyone knows already, but this is a reminder not to act too reverently.”

Events like this were always held without social ranks, so a natural laugh fell from the audience as the atmosphere of the hall became less tense.

“I don’t see Haruto...” Miharu muttered as she looked around the hall. Sara followed her gaze, glancing around.

“Yes... maybe he’s attending late?” she said, though the head elder continued to speak without concern.

“Now, if the two of you could please enter,” Syldora said, summoning Aishia and Dryas, who had been waiting outside the room.

Upon closer observation, Ursula and Dominic both had wicked grins on their faces, but no one had noticed as of yet. The doors of the hall had already been opened by people assisting the process, and everyone present — including Miharu, Sara, and the others — naturally had their gazes drawn by the doors. Immediately after, those in attendance stirred with noise.

While Aishia and Dryas certainly did enter from outside the room, they were accompanied by a third person who had been intentionally hidden away — Rio. He was sandwiched between Aishia and Dryas, each holding onto an arm of his. He had a rather uncomfortably strained smile on his face. Aishia wore her usual absentminded expression, whereas Dryas’ pleasant smile was truly impressive.

“Rio?!” Sara’s eyes widened as she accidentally raised her voice to the level of hysterics.

“O-Ooh...” Orphia and Alma also widened their eyes in surprise.

The spirit folk villagers present were half-surprised and half-speechless, in awe of seeing two humanoid spirits, Aishia and Dryas, walking together.

“Ahaha. Rio’s really something, huh?” Anya’s cat ears and tail flickered to and fro as she laughed with amusement.

Humanoid spirits ranked high class and above were practically regarded as sacred beings by the spirit folk; to be accompanied by two such goddesses on each side was an act of the highest honor to the spirit folk — or rather, an act of the greatest amusement to Anya. The three head elders watched the reactions of the attendees and smiled at how humorously their plan had succeeded.

Rio continued to escort Aishia and Dryas until they reached the stage beside the head elders’ seats.

“Now that the surprise has been revealed, I’d like to introduce everyone to Lady Aishia, who has come to visit our village today. I’m sure many of you are already aware, but Lady Aishia is Lord Rio’s contracted spirit. She was asleep for a long, long time, so her memories are still rather vague, but the chance meeting with a new humanoid spirit is a tremendously auspicious event to our people. That is why we have decided to hold a small banquet in celebration tonight,” Syldora said warmly.

“Tonight will also act as the welcoming party for the three new friends Lord Rio has brought to us. As our sworn friend, any friend valued by Lord Rio is a friend of ours, too. Let us welcome them to our village lavishly, so that they may enjoy the duration of their stay. Let’s see... How about the three of you come up to the stage?” Ursula said.

“Huh?” The three of them flinched and nervously looked around the excited hall. Rio chuckled at their reaction.

“It’s all right, Miharu. Please, come this way.” He called the eldest, Miharu, up first. She took a deep breath and timidly started walking toward the stage. Once Miharu had started to move, Aki and Masato soon followed.

“Welcome, Miharu,” Aishia said to her quietly as she approached.

“Y-Yeah, thanks. There’re a lot of eyes on us... ahaha. I might be a little nervous... Uhh...” Miharu said, grinning shyly as she turned to face the room. Once she made eye contact with the rest of the villagers, her face turned bright red, and she bowed up and down. Aki and Masato hid behind her, while the spirit folk villagers watched over the three with warm gazes.

“Gosh, your surprise went too far, Haruto,” Masato sighed.

“Sorry, I didn’t really understand the progression of things, either. They won’t do anything bad to you, so just go along with it,” Rio replied with a wry smile.

“B-But I’ve never stood in front of so many people before. It’s pretty nerve-wracking.” Even the usually cool Aki was speaking in quite a high-pitched voice. Rio nodded in understanding.

“You can see how they are, so please go easy on them, Syldora,” he said.

Syldora laughed heartily and nodded, looking over the room. “Hahaha, all right. Everyone: as you can see, our three new visitors are lovely people. Let us give them a warm welcome, so that they may adjust to life in our village as soon as possible. Please, raise your glasses.”

The audience raised their glasses in turn, and a waiter came over to Rio and the others on the stage with a tray of cups. Then, once everyone had a drink in their hand, Syldora raised his cup into the air and led the toast.

“It looks like the cups have gone around. Now, to celebrate this wonderful meeting of fate. Cheers!”

The attendees also raised their glasses in an uplifted manner. “Cheers!”

“Alright — it’s time to talk, drink, and make merry! The young ones should make sure to use this chance to humbly greet Lady Aishia and the other visitors. Go on.”

In order to enliven the banquet, the alcohol-loving Dominic took the initiative; he walked around briskly and relentlessly addressed the younger villagers, urging them toward the stage. Then, young boys and girls of the village — those acquainted like Sara’s group and those unacquainted — all started to move toward Aishia, Miharu, and the other visitors.

Sara and the other girls approached Rio first, offering to take on an assistant role for Miharu’s sake. “Leave Miharu’s support role to me. Rio, you support Lady Aishia.”

“That’d be a great help. Thank you.”

“Yup. All right, Miharu. Come this way.”

Sara and the others quickly took charge and led Miharu’s group a short distance away from the stage. Having everyone gathered in one place made it hard to manage; Sara probably intended on splitting up the crowd a little this way. Her idea seemed to work, as a decent number of people gathered toward Miharu, Aki, and Masato.

The young children of the village actively started to talk to them, immediately starting a kind of cultural exchange. Thanks to Sara and the spirit folk girls acting as an icebreaker, Miharu and her group weren’t as nervous as they could have been. It was a good atmosphere.

Looks like that side will be fine. I’ll have to do my best, too, Rio thought in relief, then braced himself.

“Everyone, feel free to come this way. I will introduce Aishia to you.” He invited those who looked eager to talk to Aishia to come closer. While they had set ranks outside of this event, they were still feeling inferior in front of their deity of worship. Then, the youngsters of the village gathered around Aishia, greeting her in awe. Aishia didn’t respond with many words, but Rio kept the conversations going well in her stead.

Furthermore, the adults of the village kept the banquet lively during that time, turning the hall into quite the busy place. There were many laughs to be had as time passed.

Just like that, nearly an hour went by in the blink of an eye.

“Fufu, it’s turned into a good welcome party. I’m having a lot of fun, too,” Dryas said to Syldora and Ursula, who were watching over the banquet in a corner of the hall. For the record, Dominic was still actively heating up the banquet from where he was.

Syldora noticed Dryas’ presence and happily addressed her. “It is a great honor to hear that you are pleased, Great Dryas.”

Ursula nodded along happily, slowly turning her gaze toward where Rio and Aishia were on the stage. “However, Aishia’s identity still remains a mystery... possibly even more so now than before. I thought she may have possibly been one of the upper high class spirits that disappeared in the Divine War, but...” she said a little uneasily.

“Hmm, good point. She does have a lot of latent power within her, I believe. I don’t know if it’s a side effect of her amnesia, but she doesn’t seem to understand how to use her powers properly as a spirit, and I’ve never heard of a humanoid spirit having aptitude for every element before. If we fought seriously, I wouldn’t be able to win.” Dryas had a rarely seen expression of contemplation on her face as she nodded.

Similar to how people had their own strengths and weaknesses in spirit arts elements, spirits also had elements that they had a higher aptitude for than others. This rule was more prominent in spirits ranked middle class and higher — that was common knowledge among the spirit folk, until now.

This was because a low class spirit — even if it didn’t have any strong or weak elements — could bloom in a particular element upon ranking up in class. From there, it would become a spirit that specialized in that element. It wasn’t as though middle class spirits and higher couldn’t use spirit arts of other elements, it was simply that their efficiency in those other elements was far worse compared to their specialty.

While humans who could use a number of different spirit art elements and people who could use all kinds of spirit art elements were a rare phenomenon, there had never been a confirmed case of a middle class spirit or higher. At most, there would appear the rare spirit with multiple elements that they had enough aptitude to specialize in at once. Presently, Dryas herself was a high rank spirit that mastered the element of earth, and even the six former upper high class spirits were said to each have their own specialty element.

And so, neither Dryas nor the village elders had expected the response from Aishia claiming to specialize in every element, so their earlier conversation had truly been shocking to them.

“For the Great Dryas to give this much praise, both Lady Aishia and Rio must be tremendously exceptional... Perhaps even more than the former upper high class spirits that vanished...” Syldora said with great awe for Aishia.

“The six upper high class spirits that formerly stood at the top of their element ability, and the single spirit that is at least high class who has the aptitude for every element... I wonder which is the more peculiar existence.” Dryas smiled, showing a glimpse of her great curiosity.

“Well, it seems neither Lord Rio nor Lady Aishia recognize their own peculiarity yet,” Ursula said, laughing heartily.

People and spirits had elements they were strong and weak in. It was extremely rare for anyone to be proficient in every element — it seemed that Rio had a slightly warped understanding with regard to the history of spirit arts, as he wasn’t quite aware of how rare that occurrence was amongst humans and spirits.

In reality, low class spirits aside, any spirit middle class or higher would — without exception — form a specialty in a particular element, making it impossible to have aptitude for every single element. But knowledge of spirit ecology like this was a rather specialized field, which was why it was understandable that Rio had misunderstood until now.

“I’ll teach him all the knowledge he needs to know about spirits during his stay in the village this time. It’s been a long time since my curiosity has been piqued like this, after all,” Dryas said, watching Rio and Aishia as they continued to chat with the villagers.

◇　◇　◇

The welcoming party for Aishia and Miharu’s group continued late into the night, but their lively time together was over in a flash.

“Now, let’s go home!” A slightly drunk Sara led the way happily, leading Rio and the others to the house they were moving into. They stepped out of the town hall and the cool spring night breeze wrapped around their bodies.

“Phew, I ate and drank to my heart’s content!” Masato said with a small burp as he patted his stomach.

“Geez, you’re like an old man, Masato,” Aki sighed. Miharu and Latifa laughed in amusement at the siblings’ exchange.

“By the way, I heard that you guys would be staying together during our time in the village...” Rio said to Sara and the others.

“Yes. The head elders have ordered us to stay together, saying it’d be the fastest way to get them used to life in the village. Ah, we’ve already checked for Miharu’s approval on this.”

“Of course, I’ll be staying with them, too!” Latifa said, clinging to Rio’s arm tightly.

“I know.” A soft smile pulled at Rio’s lips as he gently petted Latifa’s head.

“Fufu, it reminds me of those days we lived together. I’m looking forward to it... I’m sure it’ll be so much fun,” Orphia said, smiling pleasantly.

“It might get much noisier this time around,” Sara said with a sigh, making Alma laugh teasingly.

“Sara’s been looking forward to it for a while, now.”

“A-Alma, too. Anyway... All the rooms have been prepared already, so once we get to the house, we’ll decide who sleeps where.” Sara turned away with embarrassment, then increased her walking speed; her faintly blushing cheeks were probably because of the alcohol.

“Ehehe, I want to try sleeping in the same room as everyone so we can all talk together,” Latifa said with a cheerful smile.

“Huh? E-Everyone?” Masato replied in a fluster, but Aki shot him down.

“Everyone other than you, of course.”

“D-Don’t say that! Why is it okay for Haruto to do that, then?!” Masato whined in a pathetic voice, making all the girls laugh in good humor. They continued to chat noisily together and arrived at the house within a few minutes.

Alma felt her center of gravity drop with a jerk. Apparently she had fallen straight into Rio’s throwing trap, as she was grabbed by the chest and lightly thrown toward Sara.

“Waah!” Sara had been about to attack Rio from behind when Alma came flying toward her, making her dodge her in a fluster.

“I can’t believe you dodged that, Sara!” Alma objected.

“We both would’ve been taken out if I tried to catch you!”

In that time, Rio had braced his sword once again and started to run toward Sara.

“Guh, Alma — quick! Pick up your weapon!” Sara just barely managed to block Rio’s attack as she ordered Alma. Alma rolled against the ground to land safely and started running, when Orphia’s voice echoed from the sidelines.

“Sara, fall back!”

Sara backstepped reflexively. Soon after, countless crumbled lumps of dirt scattered around the open space and attacked Rio.

She used the dirt wall I used to defend myself earlier. Rio determined that Orphia had been hiding in his blind spot behind the dirt wall when she attacked him, then backstepped to face the incoming clumps of dirt. He flicked away the bothersome dirt lumps with his sword and feet.

While Rio was evading the attack, Orphia prepared an extra large water bullet with spirit arts and fired it. The water bullet arched in a gentle parabola through the air and came down on Rio’s head with a great amount of force. But Rio leapt, pouring a large amount of essence into his sword and slicing it in a single splashing stroke. The water that had been split violently went rushing toward the floor.

At the same time, Sara and Alma both attacked Rio from opposite sides once again.

“Our timing was perfect this time,” Sara said with a grin. Alma was closing in on the opposite side, forming the perfect pincer attack. Just like earlier, dealing with one of them would leave no time to intercept the other. However—

“?!”

The very next moment, a large blast of wind blew out from around Rio.

“Kyah?!” Sara and Alma both let out a scream as they were blown away. Then, Rio approached the fallen Sara and pointed his training sword at her.

“...I yield,” Sara groaned with disappointment, admitting her defeat.

“That’s enough! The victor is Lord Rio!” Uzuma declared.

“Ugh... so you were gathering ode within you as you were dealing with Orphia’s water bullet,” Sara said to Rio with a pout.

“I could tell you and Alma were about to attack me right away. I thought it’d be more efficient to take the both of you out at once, since you decided to come at me together.” Rio nodded with a wry smile.

“So you’re saying we fell right into your trap... Ugh...” Sara sighed.

“Ahaha, looks like we lost,” Orphia added as she approached.

Alma also walked over with a small sigh. “Looks like we have a lot to learn. Rio toyed with us again this time.”

“It wasn’t my intention to toy with you — it was actually a good training experience. Your coordination as a trio was wonderful,” Rio said in support of the three of them, smiling softly.

“That’s not what I meant...” Alma murmured quietly, recalling how she was treated like a little girl during the match. However, her words didn’t reach Rio’s ears.

“It was a splendid match. Lord Rio, if you would face me next!” Uzuma stepped forward as Rio’s next opponent in high spirits.

“Sure, it’d be my pleasure,” Rio agreed readily, then had his sparring match with Uzuma. Miharu and Aki watched on in astonishment, while Masato gazed at the mock battle with a fire burning in his eyes.

◇　◇　◇

After the sparring match, Rio and the others returned home to take a break. Rio took the initiative to serve the food, while Miharu and Orphia immediately volunteered to help, preparing tea and snacks for several people. In that time, Vera and Arslan led a heated conversation about the sparring match they just witnessed.

“The coolest part was when you tore Orphia’s water bullet apart with a slash of your sword!”

“No no no, the highlight of that match was when he released that blast of wind with spirit arts!”

Vera and Arslan went back and forth, discussing which moment was the highlight of the match between Rio and Sara’s group. Apparently, they both had a particular instance in mind they weren’t willing to give up on.

“Hmph! What do you think, Latifa?” Vera asked.

“Huh? All of it, I think. Onii-chan was super cool. Ehehe,” Latifa replied, smiling happily. Prompted by Vera, Latifa smiled happily as she answered.

Arslan sighed. “There’s no point in asking Latifa — she has a brother complex. What about you, Masato?” he asked.

“...Hm? Me? ...I think the most impactful moment was when Rio clashed his weapon with Alma head-on.” Masato seemed to be distracted with his thoughts, but had been listening enough to answer with a quiet tone of excitement in his voice.

“You mean when he spun around and slashed sideways?” Vera specified.

“Yeah, that was amazing. I never imagined he’d face Alma in a test of strength.” Arslan said keenly.

Alma turned her cool gaze to Arslan. “Why is that unimaginable to you?” She was aware her race had monstrous strength, but it left her maiden heart with mixed feelings.

“Huh? U-Uhh, no, I didn’t mean it that way!” Arslan’s voice cracked as he shook his head. Just then, Rio and the others returned to the living room with trays of tea and snacks.

“Here, food’s ready. Were you talking about the match just now?” Orphia asked with a grin.

“Yeah, we were,” Arslan said, then eagerly changed the subject. “Oh, that’s right... Hey, Rio. Please teach me how to fight later!”

“Yeah, sure,” Rio agreed readily.

“H-Hey, umm. Could you... Could you teach me how to use a sword, too, Haruto?” Masato asked nervously.

“...Teach you swordcraft?” Rio’s eyes widened faintly.

“...Yeah. Can you?” Masato asked, watching Rio’s expression.

“Hmm... I don’t think that’s something I can decide on my own,” Rio answered ambiguously in a guilty tone, looking at Miharu and Aki.

“Ah, umm. I don’t really like dangerous things, but I want to respect Masato’s choices. Aki also agreed that it’s fine as long as it’s not dangerous...” Miharu explained timidly.

“I see. So the two of you have discussed it already,” Rio said with a slightly unsettled expression.

“Yes. Back when Sara was giving us a tour of the house, we were talking about what we wanted to do during our stay in the village,” Miharu said, watching Rio’s face.

“Shouldn’t it be okay, then? He really wants to do it. There’s no man that wouldn’t feel fired up after seeing that fight,” Arslan said casually.

“Quiet, you,” Sara scolded. “Rio has his own thoughts. He’s a guardian of Masato’s, too.”

“Ah, no, I was just thinking a little. Umm... If you asked me if it was dangerous or not, I’d have to say it’s dangerous. It’s not like sports.” Rio looked at Miharu and Aki with a troubled expression, then turned to Masato with a serious look on his face. “Could I ask why you want to learn swordcraft, Masato? If you want to do it as a sport, I can’t recommend it.”

“I...” Masato was faintly taken aback and was rendered speechless.

“There are children in the village like Arslan and Vera that have been handling weapons from a young age in order to become warriors. Everyone’s learning in preparation for a real battle. Right?” Rio said to Masato, turning to Sara for confirmation.

“...Yes, that’s right. In order to show that the lessons are real and not a game, the instructor usually beats the understanding of a warrior into the children through real combat first. Many of them give up on being warriors at that point.” Sara nodded slowly.

“Aah, yeah, that. That was scary...” Arslan muttered with a faraway look in his eyes.

“Scary...” Vera nodded in agreement.

“Masato, the children of the village are... No, the people of this world pick up their weapons knowing that a battle is a fight for one’s life. That’s what weapons exist for. If you want to pick up a weapon, you have to be prepared for that. It’d be even more dangerous if you were to take up a weapon without knowing that,” Rio said to Masato, carefully choosing his words.

“...” Masato gulped, falling silent with a contemplative expression on his face as he pondered Rio’s words.

“It’d be one thing if you were to spend the rest of your life living safely within the village, but you’re going to return to Strahl someday, right? That place is more dangerous than the village. When you fight for your life, you also risk other people’s lives. By picking up a weapon, you have to be prepared to treat even children as fighters,” Rio said with a conflicted look, telling the unfortunate truth.

The atmosphere in the room was heavy; while Sara and the spirit folk girls could understand what Rio was saying, Miharu and Aki felt like Rio’s words were directed at them, making them feel extremely uncomfortable.

“But... that being said, not being a fighter means you’ll have to resign yourself to being attacked. Being a non-combatant doesn’t always mean one will be treated gently. There may come a time when you’ll regret not having the power to fight,” Rio said in a somewhat affirmative tone.

“...Huh?” Masato noticed that the nuance of Rio’s remarks had changed, making a confused expression appear on his face.

“That’s why I’ll respect your decision, Masato. It sounded like a lecture, but if you still want to learn swordcraft after everything you just heard, I’ll teach you. In other words... I’m of the same opinion as Miharu,” Rio said with a strained smile, then looked at Masato in question. What do you want to do? his gaze asked.

“I-I... I want to learn swordcraft. I’m scared, but I don’t want to regret anything. I want to have the power to protect people!” Masato insisted earnestly.

“...I see — you truly want to learn. Then, I’ll teach you in the spirit folk style of learning through a real battle first. It’ll be harsh, okay? If you give up here, then we won’t go any further,” Rio said in a somewhat intimidating tone.

“J... Just what I wanted!” Masato agreed with determination.

“Well, you wouldn’t be a man if you backed down here. Do your best.” Arslan grinned, thumping Masato on the shoulder.

“Yeah!” Masato nodded with a smile, but a gloomy look fell over Arslan’s face.

“Well, I do believe it’ll be mentally tough as well.”

“I-Is it really that harsh?”

“Ah... Rio is kind, but... hmm. I wonder? Even the normally gentle warriors of the village do a complete one-eighty sometimes. I guess all you can do is fight to the best of your ability against a better opponent?”

“F-Fight? ...Me?” Masato tilted his head, his eyes wide.

“Yeah, with Rio. We said it was real combat, didn’t we? In the village, we use that to determine whether or not you have the aptitude to become a warrior,” Arslan explained.

“Oh, so that’s how it is. But, me against Haruto...” Masato recalled the strength Rio showed in the earlier mock battle and gulped nervously.

“That’s how things are here, so why don’t we get to it right away after this? Okay?” Rio asked Masato.

“S-Sure!” Masato nodded, his expression stiff.

◇　◇　◇

A short time later, Rio stood in the square before the town hall, prepared to spar with Masato. There had been a huge crowd of observers for the earlier match, but after the break, it was only Rio’s group that remained.

Masato was equipped in a full set of the village children’s training gear he borrowed: a one-handed sword and shield, as well as leather armor.

“While there wouldn’t be time to do so in a real match, let’s make sure we warm up properly.”

Obeying Rio’s words, Masato focused on loosening his body carefully. At the same time, Rio was silently checking his movements with a one-handed sword and shield — a combination he rarely used — while he silently practiced stances as he tested his grip. Now that he had agreed to teach Masato, a tense air surrounded Rio; it was as though he was telling people not to approach him recklessly with his whole body.

“Onii-chan...” Latifa watched Rio worriedly. No, it wasn’t only Latifa — both Miharu and Aki, as well as Sara, Orphia, and Alma were shrinking back a little at the side of Rio they didn’t usually see. However, they were unable to do anything but watch over Rio and Masato from afar.

“Umm, this is like a practical test in order for Masato to learn swordcraft, right? What exactly is involved in the teaching of understanding through real combat?” Aki asked Sara and the others, seemingly worried for her stepbrother’s well-being.

“It’s a reenactment of a battle for your life. Of course, the gap in ability means it won’t be much of a match, but the instructor acts as though it’s real combat by using a killing intent and real hostility toward their opponent. That way, we can ascertain who has the heart to keep fighting without fearing death,” Sara explained.

“H-He won’t get injured, though... right?”

“He probably will. But Rio wouldn’t hurt him intentionally and we have spirit arts to heal with, so there’s no need to worry about injuries with long-lasting effects.”

Though there was no guarantee for his mental state, Sara added to herself.

“So that’s why everything seems so tense. I’ve never seen Haruto like that before,” Aki said, her gaze fearfully pinned on Rio.

Sara and the rest of the group nodded, their expressions stiff. “...That goes for us, too.”

Then, Rio finished his preparations and approached Miharu and the others. “Miharu, Aki... Sara and the rest of you, too. It might not be very pleasant to watch, so feel free to go home and rest. There’s no need to force yourself to stay, okay?” Rio said somewhat darkly.

“Ah, no... Umm, that’s...” They exchanged glances with each other, awkwardly mumbling under their breath.

Meanwhile, Miharu slowly raised her hand and expressed her desire to observe. “Umm, please allow me watch you.”

“It may be a little extreme. Are you going to be all right?” Rio asked while watching Miharu’s face.

“I’ll be fine. Umm, since I’ll be entrusting Masato to you with this, I wanted to bear my share of the responsibility. I feel like I have a duty to see things through, too... so please allow me to observe.” Miharu spoke quietly, showing a glimpse of her firm resolve as she bowed her head at Rio.

Rio’s eyes widened faintly as he nodded, showing some surprise. “...I understand.”

“U-Umm! Then please let me watch, too! Because Masato is my little brother!” Aki asked, following suit with Miharu.

“I see... All right.” Rio nodded in agreement.

“Naturally, I’ll be watching too, Onii-chan.” Latifa declared resolutely.

“Yeah, I know,” Rio acknowledged with a faint smile. Sara, Orphia, and Alma all looked at each other and nodded.

“Please let us watch, too,” they requested.

“I’m watching. Masato’s my friend, after all.”

“Me too!” Arslan and Vera chimed in.

“So, in the end, everyone wants to watch. All right.” Rio gave up with a bitter smile and turned on his heel. If it was going to be like this, then he couldn’t afford to hesitate anymore; he had to be prepared to reveal his cold-hearted side. With that, Rio took a small breath and walked toward Masato.

“Shall we begin soon, Masato?”

“Y-Yeah!” Masato nodded nervously.

“You should relax your muscles. Your movements will be too stiff otherwise.”

“O-Okay! Got it... All right!” Masato nodded, taking a deep breath. He braced his one-handed sword and shield as well as he could; he hadn’t been taught any techniques yet, so his form was a little awkward and misshapen.

Rio readied his sword and shield, too. His left foot was in front, while his right foot was behind; this left the shield on his left side inevitably in the front. It was the standard sparring stance for a sword and shield combination taught in the Kingdom of Beltrum — he had learned during his school days.

“The sword and shield combination is the most common sword style in the Strahl region. In terms of combat against humans, it has excellent balance between offense and defense. That’s why I was thinking of teaching you this sword style too, Masato... But you can just consider any technical instruction today as a bonus,” Rio explained, standing roughly ten meters away from the other boy. “The rest... I’ll teach you as we fight for real. The match starts now — feel free to attack me whenever.”

He looked up at the sky. With a small inhale of breath, Rio quietly adjusted his concentration.

“...Huh?” Was that the signal to begin the fight? Masato wondered in confusion. However, even if he wasn’t aware of it, the battle had already long begun.

“What’s wrong? You’re not going to come at me?” Rio asked in a cold voice that was tinged with clear hostility and murderous intent.

“?!” That was enough to make Masato feel a dense aura of death; a shudder running through his body. It wasn’t only Masato — the others who were watching from the side were involuntarily shaking, too.

What... was that just now? Miharu didn’t even understand why she was shaking, but the aura just now was of a type she had never glimpsed before. She couldn’t even believe it was being released by the person in front of her... Perhaps that was why her pounding heart wouldn’t stop.

However, the amount of discomfort Miharu felt was nothing compared to Masato, who was the one actually on the receiving end of that hostility and malice. His chest ached as though his heart was being squeezed.

Come at me quickly, Rio’s gaze was demanding the entire time, but Masato’s feet wouldn’t budge.

“I’ll wait another thirty seconds. If you can’t attack me in that time, you fail,” Rio declared plainly.

“Huh?!” Masato twitched faintly in an attempt to move his sword-wielding hand. He somehow managed to raise both elbows, assuming a fighting stance full of opportunities for Rio to land an attack. Several seconds passed, when suddenly, Masato charged at Rio with a roar.

“...Uuhh, uwaaaah!”

But the sword was heavy. The shield was heavy. His body was heavy. Masato couldn’t move as he wished, and he didn’t know how to move properly. He stopped just before Rio.

Was a sword really something that could be swung at a person? Though it was a training sword without a sharp edge, swinging it with all one’s might was still enough to bludgeon someone to death. When he realized such a dangerous weapon was in his grasp, Masato faltered.

“It’s all right. No matter how you swing that sword, you won’t hit me. There’s no need to hold back. Come — hit me. Or... have you had enough? We can quit if you want,” Rio said provokingly to Masato.

“Uh... R-Raargh!” There was still some fighting spirit left in Masato, as he managed to shake his sword with impatience.

“Guh?!” Rio purposefully stepped toward the incoming attack and deflected Masato’s sword with his shield. The impact blew Masato’s sword away.

“Don’t move!” Rio yelled.

Masato froze on the spot; he belatedly realized there was a sword tip pointed at his throat and gulped nervously. If they had been using real swords, the tip would have been a few millimeters from piercing his skin.

“Your swings are inadequate. Letting go of your sword is out of the question. Pick it up and attack again. Once more, from the start,” Rio stated, pulling his sword away as he widened his distance from Masato.

“Huh? Ah...” Masato remained standing in a daze.

“What’s wrong? Pick it up already. The battle resumes now.”

“Uh...” At Rio’s hostile tone, Masato timidly picked up the sword, but the fear of having the sword tip pointed at his throat still remained, making it hard for him to move.

“...Masato. If this were a real battle, I would have moved long ago.”

“R-Right...” Masato cowered with a nod, his usual good-humored manner of speech nowhere to be seen. Despite that, he still seemed to have some fighting spirit left in him, as he picked up the sword, trembling.

“You’re drawing back too much. Your grip is still off, too.” Rio walked up to him, then swung his sword harshly to send Masato’s sword flying. It spun through the air before stabbing into the ground.

“Again. One more time. Pick it up,” Rio ordered mercilessly.

“Ah... Uh...” Masato groaned in a voice that nearly vanished.

“Hurry,” Rio said, making Masato flinch in surprise and pick his sword up. With another careless swing, he knocked Masato’s sword away once again.

“Again. Pick it up,” Rio ordered flatly.

Every time Masato picked up his sword, Rio would send it flying, sometimes pointing his sword tip at his throat. He continuously tormented Masato with his demand to fight again and again.

As the onlookers, Miharu and the others watched on with pained expressions. Aki especially, whose body gradually trembled harder as her expression twisted with the desire to speak up. However, even as that was happening, a change was certainly occurring within Masato. Despite being knocked down again and again, Masato’s fighting spirit was stimulated and he slowly began to get worked up.

“Uraaargh!” He gradually started to yell as he swung his sword, but even then, he was scared — or maybe frustrated — as his face poured with snot and tears while he attacked Rio. His movements seemed to be getting slightly better from watching and copying Rio’s actions, at least.

“That’s right. Your shield can also be used as a blunt weapon, but don’t swing it recklessly. You’ll create a blind spot for yourself.” Rio drove his sword sharply into the blind spot Masato created by swinging his shield wildly.

The tip of his sword pointed at Masato’s throat. “Again,” Rio ordered in a short tone, and regrouped.

“Uugh,” Masato groaned in frustration.

“U-Umm, Haruto!” Aki yelled in a loud voice.

“...What?” Rio turned his gaze toward Aki, his tone devoid of all emotion.

Aki faltered for a moment, then stared directly back at Rio and answered. “Uh... Ah, no... Umm, isn’t that enough? I think Masato’s understood enough about the frame of mind needed for real combat at this point.” It showed how much she treasured Masato despite all their usual bickering and insults.

Rio shook his head bluntly. “No, not yet. We’re only just finished warming up.”

Aki refused to back down. “B-But Masato’s at his limit! You’re just bullying him like this!” she said, pointing at Masato. His breathing was harsh and his complexion was pale, and both his legs trembled fiercely. Rio sighed quietly.

“Masato, do you want to give up?” he asked. A silence suddenly fell over everyone present as their attention gathered on Masato.

“I’ll...” Masato murmured, then raised his voice. “I’ll do this!” he yelled with intensity, fixing his gaze on Rio.

“Masato, you...” A sour expression crossed Aki’s face. She wanted to say more, but Masato’s glare made her close her mouth.

“I see. As long as Masato desires it, I won’t ease up.” Rio shook his head slowly, his expression emotionless.

“...I apologize for interrupting. Please take care of Masato.” Aki’s face was woeful as she bowed her head at Rio and spoke in a shaking voice. Her eyes were filled with frustrated tears.

“...Got it. Let’s resume this, Masato.” Rio nodded, immediately returning to the battle.

Ten minutes later, Masato was lying face up on the floor, mentally and physically drained to the core. “Hah... Hah...” He attempted to pick up his sword once more, but his body refused to budge.

“...That’s enough, Masato. It’s over. You did well,” Rio informed Masato gently, letting the strength drain from his own body.

Masato scraped together the energy to speak. “Is it... hah... hah... over? I can... still... go on.”

“It’s all right. I know how strong your heart is now, so I’ll be teaching you swordcraft properly from tomorrow onward,” Rio declared.

“R-Really? I-I did it.” Masato must have been relieved, as his whole body relaxed and he slumped his full weight against the ground.

“...I’m sorry. I may have been a little harsh,” Rio said with an apologetic look.

“Haha... I thought so too. But it was for my sake, right? Thanks to that, I know just how naive I was. Thanks, Haruto.”

“...You’ll become a good swordsman, Masato.”

“That’s because you’ll be my teacher, Haruto.” Masato nodded, giggling.

“Really, now...” Rio huffed with a smile.

“Looks like that’s settled, then. You were wonderful, Masato,” Sara said.

“Yup. You were really cool,” Orphia added.

“That wasn’t a test that just anyone could pass. You should feel proud of yourself,” Alma said, adding to the praise.

“Masato, good work.”

“...Well done, Masato.” Miharu and Aki also called out to him.

“You did it, Masato. Rio’s training was no walk in the park, huh?”

“Right? He was way harsher than the instructor I had!”

“You stood before Onii-chan face to face. I think you should be proud.”

Arslan, Vera, and Latifa gave Masato words of encouragement and praise, too.

“Hehe, everyone... Thank you. —Ow, that hurts, Aki.” Masato looked up at them and thanked them; his face was as bright as the clear and sunny sky. But when Aki struck him on the head, he pouted his lips.

“It’s your fault for worrying me with your recklessness.”

“Heh, so you were worried for me?”

“Shuddup.” Aki prodded Masato in the head once more.

Rio watched the siblings’ exchange. “Let’s make Masato’s favorite foods tonight, to celebrate,” he suggested.

“Ah, that’s a good idea,” Orphia agreed. “Let’s have a party! Miharu, we can cook together.”

“Sure, I’d love to.”

“Eeh, that’s not fair! I want to join in too. Make us meat patties!”

“Me too! I want to eat spaghetti!”

Arslan and Vera voiced their desire to join in.

“Hey, it’s not your favorite foods they’ll be cooking, you know?” Sara stated with a sigh.

“Ehehe, then I want to go to the hot springs with everyone after dinner,” Latifa suggested with a happy laugh.

“That sounds good. The sparring matches earlier did make us sweat a bit,” Alma nodded, interested.

Haruto, you worked hard today. Aishia’s voice echoed in the back of Rio’s mind.

...Aishia? Rio looked around his surroundings in surprise, but he didn’t see Aishia anywhere; he figured that was because she was in her spirit form, but...

Dryas taught me how to communicate with my contract partner through long distance telepathy. I’m to your left right now, but I can communicate within a one kilometer radius. Focus on the path that connects us and look my way.

Rio moved his eyes as ordered, then spotted Aishia at the corner of the square.

...So that’s what you mean. Is this okay? Rio immediately replied to Aishia through telepathy.

It’s good.

Have you finished talking with Dryas already?

Yup. We finished talking for today, so I came to find you.

I see. Will you tell me what you talked about later?

Of course. We’ll talk then.

While the people around him made merry, Aishia’s gentle voice echoed in the back of Rio’s head. That was enough to fill his chest with a strange warmth, healing him.

◇　◇　◇

That night, Rio and the others prepared an extravagant meal and held a dinner party to celebrate Masato’s ability to overcome the practical test. However, Masato was so exhausted, he fell asleep right away.

Afterward, Rio offered to watch the house as Masato snoozed away in his room, while the girls — excluding Aishia — headed for the hot springs near the town hall that they had reserved. With Rio and Masato remaining in the house, Arslan went home by himself. Aishia passed on the hot springs as she wanted to sleep, since spirits could remain clean even without bathing anyway.

After seeing the girls off at the door, Rio returned to the living room alone. Everyone had cleaned up after their meal together, so he didn’t have anything in particular to do.

Aishia seems to have fallen asleep... I guess I’ll take a bath, too. Better go get a change of clothes.

Rio stretched lightly to relieve his stiff body before heading to his room. He turned on the artifact-powered light in his room and entered.

“Haruto,” Aishia said, suddenly materializing beside Rio.

Rio’s eyes widened slightly. “...You’re still awake.”

“Yeah. I have something to tell you.” Aishia nodded.

“Oh, right... About the required knowledge of a spirit that Dryas told you about?”

“That, and about you, too.”

“...Me?” Rio responded in surprise.

Aishia nodded, peering at Rio’s face closely. “Yeah, because you’re feeling a little sad. Are you okay?”

“That’s not true... Why do you ask?” Rio swallowed his breath, watching Aishia back.

“Because you showed everyone a side of yourself that you didn’t want them to see,” Aishia stated without any hesitance at all, as though it was obvious.

“...Why do you think that?” Rio asked nervously.

“I told you in the beginning: I know everything about Haruto,” Aishia asserted in response. By the “beginning,” she probably meant the first time she woke up in the rock house. Rio’s eyes widened with shock.

“I see... So I guess there’s nothing I can hide from you, Aishia...” he said, disappointed. He let a bitter smile show through his facade.

“Yeah.”

“Ahaha, of course you’d say that. I just want to ask one thing. Was I acting weird after the mock battle?”

Aishia shook her head. “You looked normal from the outside... But deep in your heart, you weren’t.”

“It’s all right. It’s fine, Aishia.” Rio said as though he was convincing himself, shaking his head slowly, but Aishia suddenly walked forward.

“You don’t have to act strong in front of me,” she said, hugging Rio gently.

“?!” Rio froze stiff with a flinch.

“Even if it’s fine, I want to hear it. What Haruto is feeling, what Haruto is thinking,” Aishia whispered by Rio’s ear.

The strength in Rio’s body gave out as he sighed. Aishia’s warmth was so comforting — his heart felt completely at ease.

“...I do feel like I showed them something I didn’t want them to see. The truth is, I didn’t want to show them that. But if they want to live in this world, then I believe there are things they need to see. The violent and cruel side of humans,” Rio added after a moment with a mumble at the end.

“Was the reason why you didn’t want to show them because it was Miharu, Aki, and Masato?” Aishia asked, seeing through him.

“...That’s right. I wonder what they think of how I acted today... It’s possible that I scared them. When I imagine that, my chest kind of hurts.” Rio nodded, voicing a feeble whine he would have never revealed to anyone else. “But... it’s fine,” he said with a smile of resignation, as though he had sensed something.

It was true that Miharu and the others had yet to scrape the surface of this world’s values, but Rio believed it was better that way. Ignorantly believing in peace would expose them to danger, so a certain amount of exposure was necessary... but there was no need to submerge them in it. That was why they only needed to know enough to understand that they couldn’t always wander through the world with only idealistic thoughts in their minds.

Rio didn’t want to force that role on anyone else. That was why he thought teaching Masato swordcraft was the perfect opportunity; humans revealed the ugliest side of themselves when they were fighting, so if anything, it was a little better to cause them to feel fear. Not to mention —

The worlds we live in are different.

That was right — they lived in different worlds. He could no longer turn back, and the visitors to this world still had the possibility of being able to return to Earth. That’s why Rio believed this was for the best.

“I will always be with you, Haruto. I’ll accept all of you,” Aishia said, hugging Rio even tighter.

“...Thank you.” Rio hugged Aishia back softly and awkwardly.

◇　◇　◇

Thirty minutes later, Miharu was thinking about Rio as she sank into the water of the hot spring.

I’ll have to thank Haruto again sometime.

Of course, she was thinking about the situation with Masato. He respected Masato’s own will, faced him seriously in battle, and agreed to teach him how to use a sword. When Masato first said he wanted to learn swordcraft, Miharu had imagined a vague extension of some kind of sport instead. She hadn’t properly understood that swords and swordcraft were weapons and techniques that were required in a fight for your life. Perhaps, if it was Haruto — the Haruto that had memories of life in Japan — then Miharu believed that he would have been able to teach swordcraft from the perspective of a sport.

But Haruto didn’t — Rio didn’t — do that.

He clearly explained why swords and swordcraft existed, then challenged what Masato wanted to do. He must have thought that it would have been unfortunate for Masato to live in this world thinking of swordcraft as a type of sport. Miharu could keenly feel the amount of thought that Rio had put into Masato, as well as the rest of them.

Even though I should be pulling myself together, I’m still relying on Haruto for everything.

Miharu’s face fell with shame. Rather than pulling herself together, she had been unreliable, and constantly needing Rio’s support. She hadn’t done anything for Aki and Masato, as their elder. The fact that she felt pathetic was inevitable.

I can’t do anything about swordcraft myself, but... Yes — the least I can do is make sure I support Haruto properly.

Miharu nodded firmly, having made her decision.

For now, I have to find something I can do... Rio was the kind of person who could do anything flawlessly, so it was difficult to find something she could do for him. Miharu groaned quietly.

“What’s wrong, Miharu?” Latifa, who had already been soaking in the bathtub, asked her with a tilt of her head.

Surprised, Miharu shook her head. “Huh? Ah, umm. It’s nothing.”

“...Were you thinking about Onii-chan, maybe?” Latifa asked, as though she had seen right through Miharu’s thoughts.

“U-Umm... Yeah. How did you know?” Miharu’s eyes widened.

“Ehehe, because I was thinking of him too,” Latifa said, nodding confidently.

“You’re always thinking about Rio, Latifa,” Sara said in an exasperated tone, as she’d been listening to them.

“Heh. Don’t you also think about Rio at a fairly frequent rate, Sara?” Alma quipped, jumping into the conversation without a moment’s delay.

“I-I may have been doing so just now, but it doesn’t happen frequently.” Sara shook her head in embarrassment.

“Fufu, were you thinking of the Rio we saw earlier today? I was too,” Orphia said with a smile; she was submerged in the tub. Then Sara looked at Miharu, Latifa, Orphia, and Alma, the four girls who were in the bathtub with her.

“I guess we were all thinking the same thing,” she said with a small sigh.

“Hmph! I was thinking about Rio too, you know?” Vera pouted her lips as she spoke up. Aki nodded hesitantly beside her.

“Well, me too... I mean, about that mock battle between Masato and Haruto.”

“Then, what did you two think after seeing that battle today?” Sara asked Vera and Aki, watching their expressions.

“I... umm. Honestly, I was scared. I almost thought Masato was going to get killed,” Aki said with a pained expression.

“I had chills running down my spine. His intensity was amazing, even though I was just an onlooker,” Vera agreed, shuddering.

“It’s a rite of passage. It’s all in order to understand that sometimes, you need to be relentless before your opponent’s death. It might be drastic, but it’s a necessary experience in order to become a warrior. You have to learn this, so it’s better to do it earlier and in the safest situation possible,” Sara said with a strained smile.

“So if a war begins, every warrior in this village will turn to what Haruto was like today?” Aki asked timidly.

“...No, not everyone can show the same amount of vigor that Rio can — only the warriors who have crossed the line of life and death before.”

“Ahaha. I felt overwhelmed by it, even though I was just watching from the sidelines.”

“Right. It gives me chills to imagine what would have happened if Rio had fought us in that state when he first wandered into this village with Latifa.”

Sara, Orphia, and Alma — the three girls who sometimes had to become warriors — each voiced their thoughts.

“...Does that mean Haruto has overcome that much carnage on the battlefield?” Aki asked, swallowing.

“In a place we don’t know, probably.” Sara nodded with a serious expression.

When we first arrived in this world, the slave trader who kidnapped us seemed to be really afraid of Rio too. Did he see it too? The Rio from today... Aki suddenly imagined, an indescribable chill running down her spine. She felt too irrationally scared to think any more than that.

Unconvinced, Vera turned to question Latifa. “Hmm, while it wasn’t a Rio that we were familiar with... Did you recognize that side of him, Latifa?”

Latifa shook her head, a fleeting smile on her face. “Nope, I didn’t either. But to me, Onii-chan is Onii-chan. Nothing has changed. What about you, Miharu?” she asked. Miharu had been silently lost in her own thoughts. Miharu seemed to search inside herself for her feelings before agreeing with Latifa.

“Hm? Yeah, I agree with Latifa. Even if there’s a side of him I don’t know, Haruto is still Haruto. I don’t think that will change.”

The Rio that had faced Masato was certainly colder and scarier than she ever imagined he could be from his usual self. However, even then, there was something sad and lonely about him. Strangely, that didn’t make him feel like a different person to Miharu. Perhaps it would be better to say that the Rio Miharu knew hadn’t changed at his core.

That being said, when she thought about that Rio, something strange within her chest stirred, as though he was somewhere far away, despite being right nearby. With that as her only concern, Miharu gave a pained smile.

“Ehehe, I see. Then you’re just like me.” Latifa nodded happily.

“...Yeah, just like you.” This time, Miharu was able to smile happily, and the painful stirring in her chest quieted down a little.

“I see. That’s true — Rio is still Rio. I think I understand now!” Vera also seemed to comprehend something, beaming widely.

“Hmph, it feels like you took the spotlight off that moment.” Sara pouted a little in protest.

“Fufu. Then that means you’re thinking the same thing. I am too,” Orphia said, smiling gently with amusement.

Caught off guard, Sara blushed deeply. “Ugh...”

“Ah, Sara’s embarrassed.” Alma grinned.

“Hmph!” Sara turned away to hide her embarrassment, the others all watching her before breaking into giggles. Sara groaned and ducked her head, cheeks turning all the more scarlet.

“Fufufu, this is fun. If only Aishia came along too,” Latifa said, a happy smile on her face.

“She’s probably turned into her spirit form and snoozing away inside Haruto right now, though she’ll sometimes turn into her physical form in her sleep and end up burying into Rio’s bed,” Aki remembered, her lips tugging upward in a grin as she spoke.

“Eeh, really?! That’s not fair. I want to sleep in the same bed with him!” Latifa exclaimed with jealousy.

“Eeh? B-But isn’t Haruto like a brother to you, Latifa? Umm, that is... wouldn’t it be embarrassing? Sleeping together with your brother...” Aki seemed to be imagining herself in Latifa’s place, her speech awkward.

“Huh? That’s not true. I want to bathe together with him, too,” Latifa replied passionately.

“B-Bathe?! Nope nope nope! Never! No matter what, that’s impossible!” Aki shook her head with a bright red face. Seeing her reaction, Latifa peered closely at her expression.

“Hmm. Do you have a brother too, Aki?”

“Huh? Yeah, I do. His name’s Takahisa.”

“Huh, really...” Latifa hummed and stared off into the distance.

“Speaking of Lady Aishia, there’s one thing I’m curious about...” Sara began hesitantly.

“What’s wrong?” Aki asked.

“U-Umm, don’t you think Aishia sticks too closely to Rio?” Sara said, watching the expressions around her.

Orphia’s elf ears twitched in interest. “Ah, that thought crossed my mind too.”

“Yeah, that’s true. Though I’m used to it by now...” Aki agreed with a wry smile.

“Has she been like that ever since you were in the Strahl region?” Alma asked, also intrigued.

They all mutually agreed on this fact because Aishia was always beside Rio. For example, they would stand next to each other as though snuggling up, and their hands and bodies would constantly make contact. It wasn’t as though Rio was pampering her, but it came across as something more natural — and it ended up catching the eyes of everyone around them.

“Hmm. But doesn’t Latifa also cling to Haruto a lot?” Miharu said with a tilt of her head, but Sara immediately shook her head.

“No, it’s something different from a sibling relationship...”

“Right. It’s hard to put it into words, but there’s something peculiar in the air between them,” Alma said, nodding.

“Rio’s a gentleman, so he usually maintains an appropriate amount of distance from her,” Orphia added.

“Yes, that’s it!” Sara jumped with fierce agreement. “Even though he’s like that, Lady Aishia gets special treatment, almost like it’s only natural for her to be attached to him so much.”

The girls continued to chat and gossip excitedly until they were done soaking their bodies.

◇　◇　◇

The next morning, after Rio finished eating breakfast, he shut himself in his room to be alone, stating that he had work to finish. Furthermore, Sara, Orphia, and Alma had business to take care of in the town hall, so they went out, while Latifa, Aki, and Masato had made promises to meet with Vera and Arslan outside to play together.

As a result, Miharu and Aishia were the only ones left in the living room.

“So the three of us are watching the house. It feels kind of refreshing... And it’s been a while since I’ve been alone with Ai-chan.” Miharu sat on the sofa and faced Aishia, grinning happily as she spoke.

“Should we call Haruto here to join us?”

“Fufu, we can’t. I’m sure that’d be fun, but Haruto has things to do in his room.”

“Okay... Then it’s just the two of us. What’ll we talk about?” Aishia nodded, then cocked her head to the side.

“Hmm. Oh, I know. Can I ask you a question? Since it’s just the two of us, I wanted to ask you something about Haruto...” Miharu said, remembering something she wanted to bring up.

“What is it?”

“Haruto agreed to officially teach Masato swordcraft, right? That was why I wanted to thank him for that, as well as for taking care of us on a daily basis. So I was wondering if there was anything I could do for him.”

A faint contemplative look fell over Aishia’s face before she shook her head slowly. “...I don’t think Haruto wants you to thank him for that, though.”

“Yeah... I know that, but I want to do something. It may simply be for my own satisfaction, but if Haruto could be happy...” Miharu placed a hand against her chest as she voiced her inner thoughts.

“I think Haruto would be really happy if you told him those feelings,” Aishia suggested, catching Miharu off guard and making her flustered.

“Huh? T-That’s too embarrassing, saying it so directly... I’d rather do it in a way that involved some kind of gift or action, so that’s why I’m discussing it with you, Ai-chan.”

“...If it’s something from you, then Haruto will be happy no matter what.”

“I don’t think that’s true. Haruto can do anything by himself, so I can’t think of what I should do for him. All I ever do is hold him back...” Miharu said, her face falling with sadness.

“You’re wrong.” Aishia shook her head bluntly.

“Eh?”

“It’s true that Haruto can do many things by himself, but being by yourself is lonely. Having support is essential. Haruto would definitely be happy to have your support. That’s why, Miharu, you should support Haruto,” Aishia said eloquently in response to Miharu’s expression of wonder.

Miharu blinked in surprise for a few moments, before a gentle smile spread across her face. “...Yeah. Okay,” she nodded quietly.

“Good.” Aishia also gave a soft smile.

“Fufu, I’m glad I talked to you after all, Ai-chan. You really know Haruto well.”

“You should know him well, too, Miharu.”

“Huh? I don’t think so...” Miharu tilted her head curiously at Aishia’s words. “Do you know what would make Haruto happy?”

“...Hearing Miharu’s feelings.”

“Ugh, I told you that was too embarrassing. If it was just thanking him for everything he does every day, and that I wanted to repay him, then I guess...”

“...Then, will you hug Haruto?” Aishia suggested, cocking her head.

“T-That’s even more embarrassing! No way!” Miharu yelled in a fluster.

“Then you should make him a delicious meal for lunch of all his favorite foods.”

“Lunch... Lunch, huh? I’m always making that... But what are Haruto’s favorites?” Miharu asked.

“...Omelet rice. Back when Haruto was still on Earth, he loved that food as a child,” Aishia answered simply.

Miharu had a somewhat distant look in her eyes for a moment before coming to an enthusiastic decision. “Omelet rice, I see... Okay, I’ll try making it!”

“I want to help, too. Teach me how to make it the Miharu way,” Aishia requested. Since she had helped out with the cooking quite often when they had lived in the rock house together, Aishia was now able to make a few things, too, though not as well as the other two girls. She was still in training, one could say.

“Yup, of course. Let’s make a few other things together, too!” Miharu agreed cheerfully.

Thus, Miharu and Aishia started cooking together. They decided on making a stew, a salad, and cake for dessert, before quickly making their way to the kitchen.

The two girls put on their matching aprons and chose to bake the cake first. After the preliminary preparations were done, they poured the ingredients for a sponge cake batter into a wooden bowl. Aishia followed Miharu’s instructions and mixed the ingredients thoroughly. Once the flour was mixed well and the batter had a springy texture to it, Miharu added the butter she had warmed beforehand into the bowl with milk, then directed Aishia to stir it together. “Yup, I think that’s enough. We’ll add some warm butter and milk into it... Okay, now try mixing it lightly. Your aim is to give the batter a sheen.”

“Okay.” Aishia obediently mixed the contents of the bowl as ordered.

“...Yup, that looks like enough. Next, we’ll pour it into this mold. Make sure no air gets into the batter. Don’t do it too low, and go slowly...” Miharu gently guided Aishia’s hands that were holding onto the bowl.

“Like this?” Once Aishia poured the batter into the mold, Miharu placed the now-filled mold into the oven with practiced hands.

“Yes, just like that. Once we bake it for 40 minutes, the sponge will be complete. ...And there we go. In the meantime, let’s make the stew.”

Thus, the two of them cooked together while chatting happily with each other. After a fair amount of time had passed, Miharu took a chance to suddenly ask Aishia a question.

“...Hey, Ai-chan.”

“What?”

“You’ve forgotten everything from before you first woke up, but you still remembered your contract partner. You knew about Haruto, right?”

“Yeah.” Aishia gave a short nod.

“Umm, then... What kind of person is the Haruto that you knew, Ai-chan? Exactly the same person as the one you know now?” Miharu asked hesitantly, gauging Aishia for her reaction.

After a beat, Aishia responded quietly. “...Haruto is Haruto. Cowardly, with no confidence, trapped by his own past, and at a loss for what to do. Despite that, he’s a strong person that tries to do the right thing and move forward.”

When Miharu heard the abstract description of Rio’s persona, she smiled rather sadly. “You know so much about Haruto that I don’t know...”

“Maybe. But the Haruto that Miharu knows well exists, too.”

“R-Really?” Miharu tilted her head with uncertainty.

“Yeah. You just haven’t realized it,” Aishia declared confidently.

Miharu’s eyes widened in surprise before she smiled with amusement. “Fufu, you speak with such confidence, Ai-chan.”

“...That’s because I want Miharu to accept Haruto,” Aishia said, fixing her gaze on Miharu.

“I see... Okay.” Miharu ducked her head shyly before giving a small nod, then swiftly went back to cooking to hide her embarrassment.

“Are we done talking, then?” Aishia asked.

“Y-Yeah. Sorry for asking something so weird.” Miharu nodded with a smile.

After that, their time cooking together went well. Then, just as they had nearly finished the dishes, Rio appeared in the living room, immediately noticing the delicious scent wafting from the kitchen.

“Sorry, Miharu. Is this the lunch you prepared for me? Oh, and Aishia too,” he said as he walked into the kitchen. When he spotted Miharu and Aishia sporting the same aprons together, his eyes widened faintly.

“Yes, we were just thinking about coming to call you, Haruto,” Miharu replied with a smile.

“It’s filled with appreciation and affection for Haruto,” Aishia said monotonously. It was hard to tell whether Aishia was joking or saying that because she seriously believed it.

“Ahaha, we tried our best.” Miharu grinned shyly without denying Aishia’s words.

“...Umm, thank you very much. Both of you. Is that the smell of stew, by the way?” Rio thanked them with a little embarrassment, before changing the subject to the food prepared.

“Ah, yes. We’re just about to start the omelet rice.”

Rio’s expression brightened happily at the mention of omurice. “That sounds good. I was just in the mood for that.”

“Miharu’s special omelet rice... It’s delicious,” Aishia said, giving her stamp of approval.

“I-I don’t think it warrants that much praise...” Miharu muttered somewhat uncertainly.

“No, I really want to try Miharu’s omelet rice, too,” Rio requested somewhat restlessly.

“Fufu, thank you. Please have a seat and wait there, Haruto.”

He really does seem to love omelet rice, just like Aishia said, Miharu thought with a giggle as she set about cooking.

In a matter of minutes, the cooking was completed and the freshly made omelet rice was brought out to the table where Rio was waiting, along with the other dishes Miharu and Aishia had made.

“Here you go.”

“Thank you very much. Umm... What about you two?” Rio looked up curiously at how they were still standing around after setting the table.

“Ah, umm. I was hoping to hear your opinion first,” Miharu said shyly.

“I see... Then I’ll dig in while it’s still hot. If you don’t mind me...” Sensing the situation at hand, Rio took a bite of the omelet rice covered in stew rather shyly. As he chewed, the flavor of the soft-boiled egg mixed with the stew rushed into his mouth. The rice, mixed with the stew, tasted harmonious together.

“It’s delicious! This is amazing!” Rio said, eyes widening like saucers.

Miharu sighed with relief. “Really?! I’m glad. Omelet rice is actually the first dish my mother taught me how to cook. After making it so many times, it’s secretly become my specialty dish,” she said happily.

“I see, so that’s how it is. But why is it a secret?”

“Ahaha, I just haven’t had any opportunity to make it for anyone outside of my family.”

“Is that so?” Satisfied, Rio smiled with amusement.

“Umm, Haruto... Thank you for everything you’ve done,” Miharu said as she peered at his face.

Rio tilted his head curiously before returning the sentiment. “...Sure? Same here.”

Aishia watched over the two of them in silence.

◇　◇　◇

Meanwhile, Latifa, Aki, and Masato had left the house to meet up with Vera and Arslan. They were currently sitting in a corner of the village square having a picnic as they chatted together.

Laid out before them were the lunch boxes that Miharu and Orphia had made, as well as the food that Vera’s mother had prepared.

“Hey Masato, will Rio be teaching you swordcraft today?” Arslan asked as he stuffed his cheeks with sandwiches.

Masato nodded. “Yeah. He said he’d teach me here in the square in the afternoon.”

“Hmm. If you guys finish early, I’ll ask him to spar with me, too,” Arslan said with a grin.

“It’s been a long time since I’ve faced Onii-chan in a match. I think I’ll ask him too,” Latifa said, giggling happily.

“Today, I’ll be asking Sara to face me for the first time in a few days.” Vera seemed to have her mind set on sparring with her sister.

Aki watched Latifa and Vera closely. Even though the two of them look just like normal girls my age, they’re already taking lessons to become warriors. Aren’t they scared? she wondered to herself.

“Hm? What’s wrong, Aki?” Vera asked, noticing her expression.

“Ah, umm... I was just thinking about how everyone’s training like warriors already, even though you’re my age. You all went through the same initiation as Masato and still wanted to fight, right?” Aki voiced the thoughts that had been floating around in her head.

Latifa hummed in thought before answering Aki’s question. “...Hmm. I don’t think it’s right to say we wanted to fight. And if you asked me whether fighting was scary or not, then I’d say it’s scary to fight.”

“...Even though it’s scary, you fight?” Aki asked timidly.

“Yup. Because it’s more scary not having the power to fight back when you need to. Masato said it as well, but I want power to protect my loved ones. It hurts just to stand by and watch,” Latifa said resolutely, smiling at the end of her explanation. Aki watched Latifa’s expression carefully.

“That’s right. I think the same way as Latifa,” Vera offered.

“Me too. Well, there are warriors in the village obsessed with battles. Like Uzuma, who enjoys fighting against strong opponents,” Arslan chimed in.

“The power to protect...” Aki mumbled, looking at Masato.

“W-What?” Masato asked with a high-pitched voice.

“No, it’s nothing...” Aki shook her head softly.

“Fufu, so Masato wants to protect Aki.” Vera guessed at Masato’s intentions with a grin.

“Wha... N-... Y-You’re wrong!” Masato disagreed with a flushed face.

“You say that, but your blush is undeniable proof!” Vera said confidently, to which Masato desperately refuted.

“I’m telling you, you’re wrong! You’re totally wrong!”

“Well, Masato’s feelings aside, there are times where you won’t be able to have your way without power. When it comes down to it, the only one who can protect you is you,” Arslan said, bringing their conversation to an end with a huff of laughter.

“You’re just retelling what you heard from the warriors, Arslan.” Vera stared at Arslan disapprovingly.

“Guh. I-It’s no big deal, is it? I have my own thoughts about those words,” Arslan said, turning away in embarrassment.

Vera cocked her head, not quite satisfied yet. “I get what you’re saying, but hearing it from an amateur like you only has half as much impact.”

“Ahaha. Then, Aki, let’s say someone precious to you tried to protect you. How would you feel if they put themselves in a dangerous position before you?” Latifa asked with a faint smile.

“Umm, no, I don’t want that.” Aki was able to imagine it immediately; the first thing that had come to her mind was the sight of Miharu jumping in between her and the mysterious humanoid monsters that tried to attack them in the Strahl region. The next thing that came to mind were her brothers, Takahisa and Masato.

“Right? That’s why we want the power to protect others. At the very least, I don’t want to be a hindrance to Onii-chan,” Latifa said, smiling a little sadly.

“I also want the strength to protect and support my sister. That’s why I fight even if I’m scared,” Vera nodded next.

“...I feel like the fog has cleared a little... I understand how everyone feels now. If it was for Miharu and my brother, I’d fight even if I was scared, too,” she said with a gentle smile. Now she could understand why Masato had wanted to learn swordcraft yesterday; she even felt the same way.

“Oi, Aki. You mentioned Miharu and Takahisa, but what about me?” Masato asked, pointing at himself in a showy manner.

“YOU’RE going to protect ME, aren’t you?” Aki giggled happily.

“Yeah, yeah. Fine, whatever,” Masato replied listlessly, hiding his embarrassment.

“Oh, Masato’s feeling shy,” Arslan commented in amusement, with Vera joining in.

“Aki’s also getting embarrassed at how honestly Masato admitted it.”

The two siblings both blushed red and fell silent. Seeing their sibling exchange made Latifa giggle, but she felt a small feeling of doubt that was caught on something.

Aki must have meant that Takahisa person she was separated from when she said “my brother.” I wonder... Has she forgotten about Onii-chan?

◇　◇　◇

Miharu and company continued to enjoy their peaceful days in the village. Just like that, over a month and a half had passed in the blink of an eye.

One day, Rio decided to address everyone who had gathered at the dining table for dinner.

“I think it’s about time I headed for the Strahl region. It seems like Miharu, Aki, and Masato have become pretty familiar with life in this village now,” he stated.

“Okay. In that case, you can leave them to us,” Sara said, with Orphia and Alma nodding along at Rio.

“Yes. It’s thanks to all of you that I can leave without worrying.”

“Ehehe. Don’t forget I’m here, too, Onii-chan,” Latifa said, tugging on Rio’s sleeve from where she sat to his right.

“Yeah. I’m counting on you as well, Latifa,” Rio nodded, offering Latifa a gentle smile.

With a happy laugh, Latifa’s ears and tail flicked from side to side. “Yup, leave it to me!”

“And so, I’ll be leaving you three in the care of this village. There may be some developments with regard to the heroes that were summoned, so I’ll investigate those too before I return,” Rio said, looking at Miharu’s group.

“Yes, please. But... Please make sure you don’t endanger yourself when doing so... Don’t push yourself too hard?” Miharu bowed her head apologetically before looking up at Rio’s expression with worry.

“It’ll be fine. I’ll be with Haruto,” Aishia said to Miharu, quiet but determined.

“I see. If Ai-chan is with him, then I’m relieved,” Miharu smiled calmly.

“Which means Rio and Lady Aishia will be on a journey alone, huh...” Alma murmured. Beside her, Sara’s expression changed with a gasp.

Orphia was watching their reactions with a smile when she suddenly remembered something. “Come to think of it, you originally went to the Strahl region because you had business there, right? Do you have old acquaintances there?” she asked Rio.

“Yes. There’s actually a teacher I am greatly indebted to. I wanted to go and see them again,” Rio replied, a faraway look in his eyes filled with fond memories.

“Was this a teacher from the kingdom that put out arrest warrants for your false accusation...?” Aki guessed, recalling the story Rio had previously told them about.

“Yeah. It’s my teacher from when I lived in that kingdom.”

“...Say, Haruto, are you actually a noble?” Masato asked hesitantly.

“No, I’m not... Why do you ask?”

“Because you said you were dragged into the mess of some royalty and nobility.”

“Ah. That’s because certain circumstances led me to attending an academy for nobles.”

“So your teacher was a noble? Will it be okay for you to visit them?” Masato asked worriedly.

“It’ll be fine. I have utmost faith in them.” Rio shook his head cheerfully. It was a gesture that showed how much trust he truly had in this person, which was why it caught Sara’s attention. “Umm, Rio... May I ask what kind of person your teacher was?” The others also turned their ears toward the conversation in interest.

“Despite being fairly young, my teacher was an excellent sorcerer, professor, and researcher. But underneath all that was a warm and kind personality, albeit a little clumsy at times. I stood out in the academy for not being of a noble status, but they were the only one that didn’t discriminate against me.” A gentle smile was fixed on Rio’s face as he thought about Celia and recalled his former teacher’s personality.

“...When you say fairly young, around how many years old do you mean?”

“If I recall correctly... Twenty-one years old this year.”

“That really is young... It’s not too far from me in age. So that means this person started teaching in their early teens?” Sara asked one question after another.

“Yes. My teacher graduated from the same academy, skipping grades and scoring the highest marks in history. They first started teaching at Masato’s age.”

“That’s amazing. Your teacher really must be talented,” Sara said. Rio’s answer had made everyone at the table widen their eyes.

“Yeah, they must be a genius. I can’t even imagine you teaching someone else.”

“You’re only one year older than me, Aki!” Aki and Masato bickered while glaring at each other, while Sara spoke up with another question.

“Umm, is your former teacher by any chance a woman...?” she asked fearfully.

“Yes, that’s right. She was the daughter of a count. No, she may already be married into another family by now...” The possibility of Celia being married suddenly crossed Rio’s mind, but he decided the chances were low and smiled wryly. She had often whined that she didn’t want to think about anything other than her research.

“A count? If I recall correctly, that’s a high ranking noble family in the system that the humans of the Strahl region decided upon. So Rio knew someone like that...” Sara said, quietly humming to herself in contemplation.

“Typical Onii-chan. Looks like an unexpected obstacle has appeared, huh?” Latifa turned to murmur quietly to Sara and Alma sitting nearby, but she had a somewhat delighted smile on her face. Sara and Alma cleared their throats quickly.

“...At any rate, there’s no need for you to worry about us, Rio. Please go make your way toward Strahl without any reserve. I pray that you can meet your teacher,” Sara concluded, feigning calmness.

◇　◇　◇

Two days later, in the early morning hours, Rio and Aishia were in the town square, being sent off by a group of their close friends. Once everyone present had more or less all said their goodbyes, Dryas came over.

“Aishia, make sure you support Rio properly,” she said.

“Yeah. Thank you, Dryas, for teaching me so many things during our stay,” Aishia replied.

Dryas gave a small shrug of her shoulders. “I simply taught you how to use your power and the fundamental basics of being a humanoid spirit. You’re very talented, so you remembered things quickly.”

“Allow me to thank you, too, Great Dryas,” Rio spoke up.

Dryas shook her head in a friendly manner. “It’s fine, it’s fine. However, Aishia seems to be so powerful, it makes it hard for her to suppress her aura when she’s in her physical form. Just keep that in mind. Her aura should be pretty much undetectable when she’s in her spirit form or inside your rock house with the same barrier as the village, though,” she warned. Spirits could detect each others’ presences, and it seemed like Aishia’s was particularly strong.

“...I’ll remember that, thank you,” Rio nodded with a solemn expression.

“Well, you don’t need to be too nervous about it. There are barely any stray spirits in the Strahl region, and there aren’t many spirits who would voluntarily approach a higher-ranked spirit, either. You should just let Aishia do as she wants,” Dryas said, smiling gently.

“Okay,” Rio said with a nod.

“That’s all I have to say to you. Go and pay attention to those children now,” Dryas giggled, looking over at where Miharu and Sara stood with the others in wait. That was when Latifa jumped forth from the waiting circle.

“Have a safe trip, Onii-chan!” she exclaimed, hugging him first.

“I’ll be going now. Everyone, take care of yourselves.” Rio patted Latifa gently on the head before addressing the others.

“Yes, be careful. Oh, and it seems like Miharu has a present for you?” Sara said cheerfully, looking at Miharu.

“Ah, yes. Umm, I made this lunchbox, so... Umm, please take it, if you’d like.” Miharu stepped forward shyly and offered a wrapped lunchbox to Rio.

“...Thank you very much. But when did you have the time for this?” Rio’s eyes widened as he accepted the package.

“Miharu woke up really early to make it,” Orphia said, grinning as she looked at Miharu. Alma also looked at her with a tranquil gaze.

“It was a good display of your housewife skills, Miharu.”

“N-No, not at all. I just figured a lunch would come in handy on a trip...” Miharu shook her head in embarrassment. Rio grinned happily.

“...I’ll gratefully accept this, Miharu. Thank you.”

“N-No worries. I hope it suits your tastes,” Miharu said, blushing further.

“Hohoho. I am most envious, Lord Rio,” Ursula interrupted with a hearty laugh.

“I’ll say. A sensible woman with good cooking skills is quite the catch, Rio, my boy.” Dominic also burst into hearty laughter as he joined in on what Ursula had to say.

To hide his embarrassment, Rio lightly brushed off Ursula’s and Dominic’s remarks. “Ahaha, thank you for coming to see me off, too, head elders. I’ll be going now.”

“Indeed, make sure to take care of yourself. May the blessing of the spirits guide your way, Lord Rio... Oh, and Lady Aishia, too. You could say you’ve already been extremely blessed to begin with,” Syldora said, smiling with amusement.

“Right. Conservo.” With a chuckle, Rio stored away the lunchbox into the Time-Space Cache. Then he looked at Aishia standing beside him. “Shall we go, Aishia? Make sure you stay beside me,” he said.

“Leave it to me.” Aishia said, quietly but determinedly.

“All right, we’ll be going, then! Thank you for coming to see us off so early in the morning,” Rio said, then kicked off from the ground and slowly floated up into the sky. Waving his hand, he looked down upon the remaining people below. Aishia soon ascended beside him.

The two of them continued to raise their altitude until Rio suddenly noticed Miharu looking fixedly up in their direction.

...Miharu.

He didn’t know if she could still see them, but he smiled gently until she was out of sight. Once they rose high enough, Rio turned to Aishia.

“Let’s go, Aishia.”

“Yeah.”

After Aishia nodded in response, the two of them set off immediately. They accelerated, heading straight in the direction of the Strahl region.

Down on the ground below, Miharu watched their retreating backs grow smaller and smaller.

Please let Haruto and Ai-chan return safely. She continued to look up at the sky, praying for the safety of their journey for a while after their figures had faded.

Interlude: Talented Woman, Liselotte Cretia

Fast-forwarding a little bit in time, in the Strahl region...

The blue-haired noblewoman, Liselotte Cretia, was hosting four important visitors to her estate in the trading city of Amande — the city she governed — located in the southwest region of the Galarc Kingdom.

The important visitors were Sakata Hiroaki, the hero summoned into the world three months ago, and three members of Beltrum Kingdom royalty and nobility: Second Princess Flora, Duke Gustav Huguenot, and the noblewoman Roanna Fontaine. Not even Liselotte, daughter to the most prominent lord of the Galarc Kingdom and head of the Ricca Guild — which was renowned even in neighboring kingdoms — could afford to speak out of line in the presence of these guests.

Once Hiroaki and the others arrived in the afternoon, they were first led to the dining room for a meal and introductions. Numerous courses of gourmet foods were served to the delight of not only Hiroaki, but Flora and the others as well. Liselotte acted as the hostess during the meal, keeping the conversation going so that the group had a pleasant time.

Once everyone finished dessert, Flora spoke up. “That was a wonderful selection of dishes. The authentic pasta here is different compared to anywhere else, and that cake for dessert was very delicious, too.”

“Yeah... You must have a really skilled chef here. I never expected to eat pasta in another world, but... this I can say for certain: that was the best meal I’ve had since coming to this place,” Hiroaki, who sat next to Flora, said in satisfaction. In all honesty, Hiroaki hadn’t expected much from the food in this world, but he was now reconsidering that perception.

“Hero, Princess Flora — I am most honored to receive your compliments. Allow me to graciously thank you on behalf of our head chef.” Liselotte bowed her head humbly, showing gratitude with great respect.

“Yeah, you can tell him he’s so good that I’d love to scout him as my personal chef.”

“I’m afraid that would be a problem for me, but the thought is much appreciated.”

“Ah, well, it was good enough to make me consider that,” Hiroaki said with a huff of laughter. He had actually eaten two extra servings of pasta, so even if he had said it was bad, it wouldn’t have been very convincing.

“Fufu, thank you very much. I had heard that the hero hailed from another world, so I was worried that the meal wouldn’t be to your tastes. Your words just now have reassured me,” Liselotte said, smiling brightly with relief.

For a moment, Hiroaki lost himself in Liselotte’s smile. To hide his embarrassment, he brought up another topic. “Ah, I see. That’s good, then. Pasta is the local specialty of this city, right? There’s actually a similar food in the world I’m from.”

Flora widened her eyes. “Oh my, is that true?” she asked.

“Yeah. We also have lots of other similar plants and animals. Recipes and cooking skills aside, I’m honestly glad to see there isn’t that much difference in the food here,” Hiroaki replied, remembering all the foods he’d eaten since coming to this world.

Afterword

Hello, everyone. This is the most indebted Yuri Kitayama. I’d like to thank you all for picking up Seirei Gensouki: Spirit Chronicles Volume 5: The Silver Bride.

Like the cover illustration depicts, this volume features the long-awaited full return of Professor Celia since volume 1. It took eleven months from the release of volume 1 to the release of this volume 5, but... personally, the time passed felt both long and short to me. Perhaps it felt much longer to those who were patiently awaiting Professor Celia’s return.

However, I was only able to write volume 5 because of the ample space that volumes 2, 3, and 4 opened. The contents of volume 5 greatly differed from the web novel, but how was the sight of Professor Celia in her wedding dress? If you thought it was well worth the wait, then I would truly feel blessed as an author!

By the way, I’m currently in the middle of plotting out volumes 6 and 7. The contents of those will be vastly different to the web novel, too. Or rather, it may be best if you considered the light novel and web novel to be independent and separate stories developing in parallel worlds. For now, it seems like there’s an announcement for volume 6 at the end of the book, so make sure you check that out!

Ah, that’s right — thankfully, a character introduction will be added from volume 5 onward. Unfortunately, there are many characters that appear in this story, so I had it created laboriously and extravagantly. Hopefully it will be of use in triggering your memories.

One more thing: I have an important announcement.

I mentioned this in the author profile on the cover sleeve, but the manga version of Seirei Gensouki: Spirit Chronicles has been decided! The wonderful character designs by Riv will now take life in a manga world. Just imagining it makes my chest burn hot.

I expect there’ll be many new readers coming from the manga in the future, but I consider that to be all thanks to the readers who have supported Seirei Gensouki: Spirit Chronicles until now, as well as all the related parties that participated in the editing and marketing departments. I’d like to use this space to offer my sincere gratitude to you all. Thank you very much!

Just between you and me, I admire both Riv, who is in charge of the illustrations, and tenkla, who will be taking on the manga, so much. I am most obliged to them.

Furthermore, I appreciate all the love I have received from the readers as the number of volumes increases. My editors, and all other involved parties working where I can’t see have really been so reliable. I truly feel so blessed. I would have never been able to stand here of my own power alone. I’m still a newbie, and I’ll be working my hardest not to drag anyone else down, but I would greatly appreciate it if you continued to support me. Thank you very much.

Now, as for details regarding the manga version, I believe there will be various announcements made on HJ Bunko’s official website and blog (it’s possible that by the time this volume is released, some information will have been announced already), so please do check those out if you have the time.

Also, I occasionally tweet announcements and things on my Twitter account to my followers, so feel free to check there, too.

Finally, I still have some space left, so allow me to take this chance to tell a story from a party held by HJ Bunko the other day. I got the reaction of “Eh, you’re Kitayama?!” from the people I met, but what kind of image do you all have of me? (laughs) I felt kind of bad for being your regular old average Joe. (laughs) Well, then — I hope we can meet again in volume 6. Please continue to give your support to Seirei Gensouki: Spirit Chronicles!

— 2016, end of July, Yuri Kitayama